<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A letter to some divines, concerning the question, whether God since Christ's ascension, doth any more reveal himself to mankind by the means of divine apparitions? With an exact account of what God hath bestowed upon a noble maid, from her seventh year, until now, MDCXCI. Written originally in High-Dutch, and now set forth in English by the editor of the Laws of paradise, newly published.</title>
            <author>J. W. P.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1695</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 197 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 87 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A56584</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P72</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R222652</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99833800</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99833800</idno>
            <idno type="VID">38278</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A56584)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 38278)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1785:01)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A letter to some divines, concerning the question, whether God since Christ's ascension, doth any more reveal himself to mankind by the means of divine apparitions? With an exact account of what God hath bestowed upon a noble maid, from her seventh year, until now, MDCXCI. Written originally in High-Dutch, and now set forth in English by the editor of the Laws of paradise, newly published.</title>
                  <author>J. W. P.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[44], 129, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed, and sold by John Whitlock, in Stationers-Court, near Ludgate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1695.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed on p. 126: J.W.P.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Jesus Christ --  Apparitions and miracles --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Kayla Ondracek</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A LETTER To Some DIVINES, Concerning the Queſtion, <hi>Whether GOD ſince</hi> Chriſt<hi>'s Aſcen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, doth any more Reveal himſelf to Mankind by the means of Divine Apparitions?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>With an Exact Account of what God hath beſtowed upon a Noble Maid, from her Seventh Year, until Now, MDCXCI.</p>
            <p>Written Originally in <hi>High-Dutch,</hi> and now ſet forth in <hi>Engliſh</hi> by the Editor of the LAWS of PARADISE, newly Publiſhed.</p>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>1 Cor. 2.16.</hi>
               </bibl> Who hath known the Mind of the LORD, that he may inſtruct him? But we have the Mind of CHRIST.</q>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed, and Sold by <hi>John Whitlock,</hi> in <hi>Stationers-Court,</hi> near <hi>Ludgate.</hi> 1695.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>TO THE Engliſh READER.</head>
            <p>MAny and Vain have been the Pretenſions to <hi>Inſpiration</hi> in all Ages of the World, even <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>o many, as to make one almoſt doubt of the Reality of Any Thing, that would be thought to be of that kind. If God has had his Prophets, the Devil has always had his in much more abun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dance; and he has learnt ſo well to transform himſelf into an Angel of Light, that it requires, perhaps, ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing more than Man to trace out his Windings, and pluck off his Vizard. Hence it is that ſome Conſidering Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, and thoſe, as there is reaſon to believe, of Good Intentions, have at the end, after long Search, and Puzlings of their Brain on this Head, been temp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to conclude, that whatever goes be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yond the Reach of the Ordinary Light
<pb facs="tcp:38278:3"/>
of Reaſon, or Claims to be deriv'd from an higher Source, is Uncertain, and altogether Unſatisfactory. Whence they have thought it ſufficient to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve the Laws of <hi>Natural</hi> and <hi>Moral</hi> Religion: And for fear they ſhould be Impos'd upon, have cut the Knot at once; and ſo, without fairly weigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Arguments on both ſides, have too haſtily decided the Controverſie, in favour of <hi>Human</hi> Reaſon againſt <hi>Divine</hi> Revelation.</p>
            <p>Others who are convinc'd of the Corruption and <hi>Degeneracy</hi> of our Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, the <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ncertainty</hi> of Human Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoning, and the <hi>Imperfect</hi> Knowledge which we have <hi>at beſt</hi> of the Divine Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or of our own Spirits and Souls have thought it abſolutely impoſſible without the aſſiſtance of a more than Ordinary Illumination, from Him who is the Fountain of Lights, to arrive at any True Diſcerning in the Concerns of Religion. Hence they have deter<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>min'd it Neceſſary, and Included in the very Notion of a God, which ſup<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>poſes the Care of All that has proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed
<pb facs="tcp:38278:3"/>
from Him, that God ſhould ſend his Prophets, Apoſtles, Evangeliſts, and other Inſpir'd Teachers, to inform us of our Preſent and Future State, ſo far as is needful for us to know; to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moniſh us of our Duty; to keep up in us a Senſe of his All-directing Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence; and to Foretel, and Prepare our Minds, for the reception of the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rious Diſpenſations of his Love and Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice; <hi>For the Perfecting of the Saints, and for the Building up the Body of Chriſt,</hi> that by the means of Theſe, we may <hi>grow up into Him, who is the Head.</hi> But all this, ſay many among the Great, the Wiſe, and the Learned, has been ſufficiently provided for already: God has reveal'd his Holy Will to us in the Scriptures of the <hi>Old</hi> and <hi>New</hi> Teſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, the Canon of which is now Seal'd up: Chriſt, having abundantly Inſtructed his Diſciples in all that's Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary to make Mankind Happy, whilſt he Convers'd with 'em here Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low, is now Aſcended up on High, and ſpeaks no more to us, but in that Book, which He has left behind for the Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary
<pb facs="tcp:38278:4"/>
Guidance of his Church, until he ſhall come again <hi>in like manner as he was ſeen to go up:</hi> He has alſo forewarned us, that in the Latter Days many Falſe <hi>Prophets,</hi> and Falſe <hi>Chriſts</hi> ſhould ariſe, who would <hi>deceive, if it were poſſible, the very Elect.</hi> We have <hi>Moſes</hi> and the <hi>Prophets,</hi> yea, we have <hi>Chriſt</hi> and the <hi>Apoſtles:</hi> Therefore 'tis juſt that we ſhould cleave to theſe Alone, without looking for any <hi>further</hi> Revelation or Manifeſtation from God; leſt we ſhould come to be Deluded by Dreams, and Legends or Tales of <hi>Women,</hi> and to be carry'd about <hi>with every Wind,</hi> or Spirit, <hi>of Doctrine, by the ſleights of Men lying in wait to deceive.</hi> Many inſtances are produced by them, of ſuch as have Knowingly, or Ignorantly been the Inſtruments of Seduction, and have drawn in many into a Belief, not only of the greateſt Extravagances, but alſo of the higheſt Blaſphemies. And ſo many things are truly urg'd concerning the ſtrength of Imagination, and the Effects of Religious Melancholly, that I do not much wonder at 'em, for ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecting
<pb facs="tcp:38278:4"/>
all that they hear of Extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Illumination, to be no better.</p>
            <p>Notwithſtanding which prejudices, I have yet met with ſome few Perſons, both Abroad and at Home, that are nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Fools, nor Madmen, of whom I do ſincerely profeſs, after much Doubting, and long Examining, that they ſeem to me aſſiſted in a <hi>Special</hi> Manner by God, for ſome Great and Glorious Ends which are as yet hid from the World. Theſe live in great Humility and Sim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicity, entire Reſignation, univerſal Love, and an Heroical Faith, that is without Doubting, without Fear, and as free from Credulity as from either: In whom I have beheld the Princely Magnanimity of the Lion, mix'd with the Meek Sweetneſs of the Lamb. With theſe they go forth Conquering, and to Conquer, in the Power of God; being Dedicated to him, and moſt aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuredly Poſſeſs'd, Enlighten'd, and Actuated by Him; not living their own Life, but His; neither ſpeaking their own Words, nor doing their own Deeds, but letting Him Speak and Act
<pb facs="tcp:38278:5"/>
all in them, whoſe Right it is to be All in All; of whoſe Nature they are made <hi>Partakers</hi> in the New Birth, having in 'em the <hi>Mind of Christ,</hi> and being truly the Temples of the Holy Ghoſt. They have their Eyes conſtantly fix'd upon the Author and Finiſher of this War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fare; for the ſake of whom they not only <hi>endure the Croſs,</hi> but what is more to a Brave Spirit, <hi>deſpiſe the Shame.</hi> They are eſpecially given to the Read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the Holy Scriptures, and they believe the Lives of the Antient Wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thies that are there Recorded, to be ſet down for them to Copy, and not to give 'em barely an Hiſtorical Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of ſome ſtrange Particulars, that are not Now any longer Practicable. They ſay, that <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets, <hi>Chriſt</hi> and the Apoſtles, have all had re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect to, and propheſy'd of, the Times that are approaching very ſwiftly: They expect in theſe Latter Days to ſee many Falſe Prophets, and Falſe Chriſts ſetting up themſelves; yea, that the Great <hi>Antichriſt</hi> ſhall be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veal'd in the Deceivableneſs of Lying
<pb facs="tcp:38278:5"/>
Wonders. But they are not at this at all ſolicitous or troubled, they know on whom they relye; they will not miſtruſt their Heavenly Father, as if he would ſuffer them to be miſled, who have given up themſelves, without re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve, to be led by Him. Let Him do, ſay they, with us as he pleaſes; we are no longer our Own, but His: We know our own Weakneſs and Inability to Guide our ſelves; and that as we cannot but Err and go Aſtray, when<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever we follow <hi>the Devices and Deſires of our own Hearts,</hi> let 'em appear never ſo Plauſible and Rational; ſo we can't but walk in the True Path, when ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving utterly renounc'd them all, we are Simplify'd to the ſtate of little Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, and made ſo perfectly Subject to Our Father, that his <hi>Will may be done</hi> no leſs in us, than it <hi>is in Heaven.</hi> We know well enough, <hi>if it were poſſible,</hi> there are ſome Crafty, Serpent-like Spirits, having an Appearance of God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lineſs, that would deceive the very E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect: But let 'em do all that they can, we are ſatisfy'd, that 'tis <hi>not poſſible</hi> for
<pb facs="tcp:38278:6"/>
'em ever to Deceive theſe, or any, that in the Inward Ground and Center of their Hearts, do ſtand in the Faith and Love of <hi>Jeſus;</hi> theſe being they, who through the pure Unction of the Spirit of Truth are fully confirm'd, and ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled rightly to diſtinguiſh Spirits, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to Section XLII. 3. of This <hi>Letter.</hi> This is their Profeſſion, and this they ſtick to. If you tell 'em of Falſe Lights and Impoſtors, of <hi>Jannes</hi> and <hi>Jambres,</hi> and the like, they anſwer you unconcernedly, that the Rod of <hi>Moſes</hi> will prevail over the Rods of all the Evil Magicians: That a <hi>Simon Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gus</hi> ſhall be made to fall down before a <hi>Peter,</hi> and a <hi>Divining Spirit</hi> to fly at the Command of a <hi>Paul.</hi> And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, ſay they, leſt we ſhould be car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry'd about with every Spirit, and with every change of Doctrine, we humbly conceive it not at all unbecoming the Goodneſs, Juſtice, and Truth of our Lord, to ſend forth Now in theſe Laſt Days, as in the Times of Old, when the Goſpel of <hi>Chriſt</hi> was firſt Publiſh'd, <hi>ſome Apoſtles, ſome Prophets, ſome Evan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geliſts,
<pb facs="tcp:38278:6"/>
ſome Paſtors and Teachers,</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructed by himſelf; for the Compleat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that which is left behind in the Saints, for the Work of the Miniſtry, even that of the Everlaſting Goſpel, and for the Building up of <hi>Sion,</hi> which is <hi>the Body of Chriſt.</hi> They ſay, that if there was need Heretofore, there is no leſs need of ſuch Now: And were there no ſuch need, they ſuppoſe that no body can deny, but that the more any one has of the Spirit of <hi>Chriſt,</hi> the fitter ſuch a Perſon is to declare his Mind. They hold the Whole Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel of God, concerning Things Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary for His own Glory, or Man's Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, to be either expreſly ſet down in Scripture, or by good and neceſſary Conſequence to be deduced from it; to which nothing Eſſentially, or in Subſtance, differing from it, is at any time to be added, either by New Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velations of the Spirit, or Traditions of Men: Nevertheleſs they not only own the Inward Illumination of the Divine Spirit to be needful, for the Underſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of ſuch Things as are there Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veal'd;
<pb facs="tcp:38278:7"/>
but do alſo believe, that as well for a more powerful Vindication of it from falſe Gloſſes and Miſunderſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, as likewiſe for a more free Publi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation of it over the whole World, God, whoſe Arm is not now ſhorten'd, will for theſe Ends, ſend out ſome Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes to all Nations with great Power, before <hi>the End ſhall come, Mat.</hi> 24.4. <hi>Rev.</hi> 14.6, 7. and Section XI. of the <hi>Letter.</hi> Nay, ſome I have found, who are not afraid to aſſert, That All the Reaſons that can be brought, why there ſhould be any New Revelation or Inſpiration after <hi>Moſes,</hi> will hold good, why it ought to be Reviv'd in theſe Times, before the Deſtruction of the Falſe Myſtical <hi>Jeruſalem.</hi> This, I confeſs, appear'd to me mighty ſtrange at the firſt, being an Aſſertion ſo oppoſite to what I had always en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertain'd: But I, who knew full well the Modeſty and Sobriety of theſe Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons in other Matters, dare not be Haſty in Condemning what they pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs to ſee, whom I muſt own in ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral things to be much clearer-ſighted
<pb facs="tcp:38278:7"/>
than my ſelf. Whether, and How they are able to make it good, I leave them to conſider, and the Event to prove. And ſince they are ready to enter the Liſts upon this Head, I de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire no more from 'em, but a Candid Hearing, who ſeek thoſe things only that make for Peace. This is a True, but Imperfect Account of a ſort of Perſons, that are Perſecuted, Afflict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and Tormented for that Living Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony of JESUS, which the World cannot bear, who are in Deriſion call'd PIETISTS: Being in both the <hi>Saxo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, Brandenburgh, Lunenburg, Hano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver,</hi> and the Countries of the Two Northern Crowns, in which places they are moſt diſpers'd, mark'd out by That, as Here by other Names. If any deſire to underſtand their Chara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cter better, they may find it in the <hi>German Divinity,</hi> a Book plac'd by <hi>Luther,</hi> but one degree below the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Scriptures, and in the<note n="*" place="margin">Tranſlated out of <hi>High-Dutch,</hi> and Printed in the Year 1685. <hi>Octavo.</hi>
               </note> 
               <hi>Golden Rule of the Travelling Soul.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:38278:8"/>Of the Number of Theſe, is the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor of this following Letter, now, af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter long Conſideration, ſet forth in the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Tongue. Who is not only of ſuch Integrity in his Life, (as I have heard it confeſs'd by ſuch as would have ſaid otherwiſe, if they could) as that he cannot be ſuppos'd to have had any Deſign to Impoſe upon others; but is alſo of ſuch Intellectual Accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhments, as well Natural as Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quir'd, that 'tis not very probable he ſhould be deceiv'd himſelf, as thoſe who intimately know him, do aſſure me. Beſides the Poſt which he in the <hi>Lutheran</hi> Church Honourably bore, and more Honourably parted with, was not ſo Inconſiderable, that any Thinking Perſon can imagine, that he, whatever otherwiſe his Inclinations might be, ſhould be guilty of a Baſe Action, without the leaſt proſpect of any Advantage to himſelf by it, but rather of the quite contrary. This then is the Caſe, He according to the Duty of his Function, having with all Accuracy Studied the Holy Scriptures,
<pb facs="tcp:38278:8"/>
finds ſeveral Great and Glorious Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſies, which cannot with any tole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable interpretation be ſuppos'd to be as yet Accompliſh'd, or at beſt but ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry imperfectly: At length after much Pains taken, that he might be able to inform himſelf and others in theſe deep Truths, he becomes known, as is ſet down Section XX, XXI, XXII, XXIII, to a Young Lady of Admirable En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dowments, who profeſſes to have been Viſited by GOD from her very Child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood, in a manner very Extraordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, which for many Years ſhe had con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal'd from the World: He examines into the matter, finds a ſurprizing Harmony in all, and every part, and many concurring Events, to eſtabliſh what he heard from her Mouth. Whereupon after about a Years time, and having had all Opportunities to try the Truth of what ſhe aſſerted; he Communicates the Matter of Fact, plainly and ſimply, in This Letter di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rected to the Clergy, holding the <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion of Ausbourg.</hi> What he did in this unbecoming the Character of his
<pb facs="tcp:38278:9"/>
Perſon, unbeſeeming the Epiſcopal Authority lodg'd in him, inconſiſtent with the Care of his own Dioceſs, or Diſtrict of <hi>Lunenburg,</hi> with his Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal Love for the whole Church of <hi>Chriſt,</hi> and with a generous Concern for the Good of all Mankind; or laſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, that a Wiſe and a Good Man would not do in the ſame Caſe, notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all the loud Cries againſt Him, I am not able to find: And I do ſincere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly aſſure every Chriſtian Soul that reads this, that if it were poſſible to have found any Real or Material Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection in any one Point, I would cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly have ſhewn it. I am not Igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant of moſt, or all, the Objections, which the moſt Jealous and Subtle Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit can here form, yet after all, am ſtill more and more, through the Grace beſtow'd on me, confirm'd in the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief hereof. Some Arguments for which, both External and Internal, I ſhall briefly hint, and leave to the Cenſure of the Judicious and Sober.</p>
            <p>Among the External Proofs for the Truth of this Matter, I place firſt the
<pb facs="tcp:38278:9"/>
Agreement of the <hi>Line of Time,</hi> or the Prophetical Meaſure: Which is not al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together to be deſpis'd, notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing it is ſo very intricate and perplex'd, and that ſo many have hitherto fail'd in it. For allowing it to be true, which is not perhaps yet altogether ſo clear, that all have yet been out in it, to ſay thence that none can ever know it, is no more than to ſay, That be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe Multitudes have been miſtaken in a Thing, 'tis not poſſible that any one ſhould be in the Right: Or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe we have ſeen none that have hit the White, 'tis not poſſible that any ſhould come near it; which would be, as if a Naturaliſt ſhould deny the poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſibility of making Salt-water Freſh, becauſe many have not ſucceeded in the Attempt.</p>
            <p>But not to lay any greater ſtreſs up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on this than it will bear, it will not be amiſs, that the Inquiſitive Chriſtian look a little into the Face of the Times, and conſider the preſent Tendencies, which he can perceive towards ſome Grand Revolution in the Church. Of
<pb facs="tcp:38278:10"/>
this not ſome few, as of the former, but every one is capable; and this likewiſe every one is oblig'd to, that believes the Goſpel of <hi>Chriſt,</hi> who for that end, gives us at large the Marks and Signs, which ſhall forerun the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the Son of Man, to deſtroy the Wicked Worldly <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> Typify'd under that Bloody City, which was raz'd by the <hi>Romans</hi> under <hi>Titus Veſpa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſianus;</hi> giving at the ſame time to thoſe who omit to do ſo, the terrible Name of <hi>Hypocrites,</hi> ranking 'em a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong thoſe who ſay, <hi>They are</hi> Jews, <hi>but are not.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Another Conſideration that might incline every ſerious Perſon, to give a more than ordinary Attention at this time, and to take the Pains to <hi>try the Spirits,</hi> whether they be of God or not, is that Univerſal Expectation in all Places, of ſomething New, that is to break forth upon the Stage of this Lower World. <hi>Germany</hi> is not the only Place, <hi>France,</hi> according to all Credible Relations, is little leſs Tin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctur'd; the Severity of that Monarch,
<pb facs="tcp:38278:10"/>
and of the Governing Clergy of that Kingdom, is not able to put a ſtop to the Growth of that <hi>Muſtard-ſeed,</hi> which is encreaſing into a Tree, that is to overſhadow the whole Earth. Neither has God left himſelf without a Seed in <hi>Italy;</hi> and what I have found there, after the moſt ſincere and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>partial ſearch that I have been able to make, is enough to ſatisfie me, that it is deſign'd by God, to be the Scene of ſome very Extraordinary Thing, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in a little ſpace of time; and that there will be ſuch a glorious Manifeſtation of his Judgment and Mercy, as never has been yet there. Neither are theſe great Expectations, accompany'd with extraordinary Motions of the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine Spirit, in ſeveral Perſons, only a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong <hi>Chriſtians,</hi> but even among the <hi>Turks,</hi> and that too among the moſt Eminently Dignify'd, and the Chief Miniſters of the <hi>Port,</hi> ſeveral of whom, as I am inform'd by ſuch as have near<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Convers'd with 'em, and whoſe Integrity, as well as Ability, I can confide in, expect only a Door to be
<pb facs="tcp:38278:11"/>
open'd for 'em, that they may profeſs, what they are in their Hearts Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinc'd of. That there is alſo ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing moving at this Day in the Spirits of the very <hi>Jews,</hi> beyond what has hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto been, and in quite another man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, is well known to ſeveral, who have intimately Diſcours'd 'em upon Divine Matters, and the Fulfilling of Scripture Propheſies. Some in <hi>Hol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land, Germany, Italy,</hi> and even here in <hi>England,</hi> have been found to give ſome Teſtimony, to ſome of the Great Things contain'd in this Letter, ſome one way, ſome another, ſome by In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terpretation of the Old Scriptures, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers by immediate Illumination, of whom, even thoſe who have not un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood it, have appear'd to them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves to have been ſurrounded with a Bright Cloud, and to behold the Vail drop from them. But I forbear, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidering that many things relating to them, and to the reſt of the Tribes of <hi>Iſrael</hi> are to be kept ſecret till the Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed Day. For the ſame Reaſon alſo, what relates to the Preparation
<pb facs="tcp:38278:11"/>
and Diſpoſition which is at this time in the <hi>Heathens</hi> themſelves, both in the <hi>Eaſt</hi> and <hi>West Indies,</hi> and how that a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong theſe laſt, in like manner as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the coming of the <hi>Spaniard,</hi> there are Expectations and Predictions of an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other ſort of Revolution to be in thoſe Parts than the former one was: As al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo for that I love not to ſpeak of any thing that is at a diſtance, without the Authority I have it from be ſufficient to make amends for the ſame, and to put me even beyond almoſt the poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility of being my ſelf deceiv'd, or of deceiving others; I ſhall not inſiſt on: but leave this, with many other things of a Particular Nature, that might be ſaid upon this Head, till the Truth ſhall Powerfully manifeſt it ſelf.</p>
            <p>Another Conſideration to incline us to a ſerious Weighing, at leaſt, of the Matter of Fact contain'd in this Letter, may be the ſeveral Miraculous Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearances that, according to the Belief of many, have lately been, and yet are amongſt us here in <hi>England.</hi> Now tho' I would not lay a greater ſtreſs
<pb facs="tcp:38278:12"/>
upon theſe, than they are able to bear, as being ſenſible, that one Falſe, or Suſpicious Miracle, is of greater diſad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage to Reveal'd Religion, than all the Real Ones of our Bleſſed Saviour, and his Apoſtles, are of advantage to it, in the Minds of many Gentlemen, who value themſelves above others, for what they call Thinking Freely; not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding this, I am not afraid to aſſert, that be they what they will, they are however <hi>Alarms</hi> to Awaken us to <hi>Try</hi> the Spirits. Which is all that I deſire, in order to the giving a Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict upon the Life of this dear Bleſſed Lady, as to that part of it which is here Recorded.</p>
            <p>Neither is that Great Inundation of Atheiſm and Deiſm at this preſent, a Sign ſlightly to be paſs'd over, of the Breaking forth of the Heavenly Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers. For were not the Spirit of God very Active at this time, in the Spirits of his Saints, the Spirit of the Prince of this World would never be ſo buſie, either to Deny him barefacedly, or to Oppoſe, at leaſt, his Return to Uni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſal
<pb facs="tcp:38278:12"/>
Nature, to reſtore it to its Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitive and <hi>Paradiſiacal</hi> State. And as there never was more Sadduciſm in the World, than when the <hi>Son</hi> of God was <hi>firſt</hi> Manifeſted in it, and did ſo many Miracles; ſo is it not to be wondred at, if it be again permitted to Triumph a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt His <hi>Second</hi> Appearance, in the Glory of the <hi>Father.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Neither doth the Breaking in of <hi>Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual Deluſion,</hi> any more than that of <hi>Sadduciſm,</hi> make <hi>againſt</hi> what I aim at; but very much <hi>for</hi> it. Both the one, and the other have been Foretold, and therefore we cannot look for ſomething Better, without we look for <hi>This</hi> too. But the great Variety of Spirits ought no more, than the Variety of Religious Opinions, or the Difference of Human Reaſonings, to diſcourage any Lover of Truth, from the Searching into ſo Great and Inſtantaneous a Concern as this. And as one who truly Honours God, will not be afraid of the Imputa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of <hi>Atheiſm,</hi> or of being counted to be of no Religion at all, in that he cannot acknowledge every thing to be
<pb facs="tcp:38278:13"/>
His Word, which the Gloſſes of Men would make to be ſo: So neither on the other ſide will he be frighten'd with a Fools Cap, or the Charge of <hi>Enthu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiaſm,</hi> ſo as to be aſham'd to own the Pure Teachings of the Spirit of Chriſt, which in all Times <hi>entring into Holy Souls, makes them Friends of God, and Prophets.</hi> Whereas indeed as nothing is more oppoſite to Atheiſm, than the true Knowledge of Nature, ſo is no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing more contrary to Enthuſiaſtick Madneſs, than the true Inſpiration of the Divine Wiſdom; and nothing ſo widely diſtant from Phanſie, whatever ſome Unexperienc'd Perſons may ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gine, as that <hi>Real</hi> and <hi>Senſible</hi> Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion with God, which our Spirits and Souls are capable of arriving to, even in This Life. And let thoſe who juſtly think, nothing to be more Dero<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gatory to the Divine Majeſty, than to be always crying out, <hi>The Word of the Lord!</hi> Or, <hi>The Finger of the Lord!</hi> Take heed on the other ſide, leſt they be found among thoſe, who go about to oppoſe the Revelations he is pleas'd to
<pb facs="tcp:38278:13"/>
give of himſelf. In theſe ſeveral ways is our good God, Awakening Men to the Knowledge of his Glory, and of the Future Times, in the Appearance of <hi>Jeſus</hi> by his Living Power in their Hearts, while the Adverſary, that knows he has but a little time longer to rage, is uſing all means to lull 'em Aſleep, or to make 'em Frantick. All ſorts of People, all Religions and Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties beſpeak as much; wonderful Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vidences, and ſtrange Revolutions and Alterations of this laſt Age, and this Iſland particularly for Fifty Years paſt, confirm as much. Theſe are <hi>General</hi> Conſiderations, and there are ſome o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers alſo, which your Aſtrological and Cabaliſtical Heads give ſome heed to, which I purpoſely omit. But there are ſome more <hi>Particular</hi> ones.</p>
            <p>Firſt, as for the Bleſſed Inſtrument of theſe Revelations, there are all the Indications of Truth and Sincerity, that can reaſonably be requir'd in ſuch a Caſe. I reckon it a very good proof of the Truth of the <hi>Chriſtian</hi> Religion, that thoſe who firſt deliver'd it to the
<pb facs="tcp:38278:14"/>
World, were Perſons that could not but be well inform'd of the Truth of what they declar'd, and could have no Temptation to Publiſh it, but all man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of Temptations to ſuppreſs and conceal it. Whence, it is to me no bad Proof of the Reality of this Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, if the Principal Inſtrument her ſelf, with ſeveral others about her, muſt needs be ſuppos'd to have had all the <hi>Moral</hi> Aſſurances of this Fact, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it be a True Inſpiration, or a Falſe Deluſion; and if a True Inſpiration, not only Moral, but alſo <hi>Divine</hi> Aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rances of the Truth of this intimate Communion with the Spirit of God: And if beſides, there can't be any one Reaſon produc'd, that ſhould tempt this Perſon to invent, and ſend abroad a Falſhood, or Heap of Falſhoods of this Nature; and if there be many Reaſons to the contrary, the Proof is ſtill ſtronger. Now thus it is here, at the very firſt view to any one, that but conſiders Her Condition and Quality in the World, the Reputation of the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily, and the Improbability (if not
<pb facs="tcp:38278:14"/>
Impoſſibility) of her not being diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover'd, ſuppoſing it a meer contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance to deceive. Which has been a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bundantly confirm'd by Experience, both before, and ſince the Firſt Publi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation of This Letter.</p>
            <p>I alſo reckon it a very great Proof of the Truth of a Thing, if it comes cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly from One, that has little Abili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to Contrive it, and leſs to Promote it. And indeed, nothing tends more to the Glory of God, than to make uſe of Weak Inſtruments; that ſo nothing may be attributed to them, but all to Him; who is a God, that loves out of the Mouths of Babes and Sucklings to perfect his Praiſe, and to begin Mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, that he may accompliſh his Work more Gloriouſly, according to Section XIII. This is a mighty Confirmation of the Goſpel of the Bleſſed <hi>Jeſus,</hi> and I do not ſee why it ſhould not be alſo of the Spirit of the ſame Jeſus, ſpeak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing In, and By the Mouth of this Elect Virgin.</p>
            <p>It alſo mightily encreaſes the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bility of a Matter, if it be confirm'd by
<pb facs="tcp:38278:15"/>
Perſons, either in different Times or Places; of whom there is no Reaſon to ſuppoſe, that they have had any Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication together, or Knowledge of, one another. Wherefore if it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear, that ſeveral Things deliver'd by this Perſon, do moſt exactly concur and agree, even after a very Nice Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, with what has been before pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dicted by a Succeſſion of Prophets, and Inſpir'd Perſons in ſeveral Ages, whoſe Authority is alſo allow'd by us, and if there be no reaſon to ſuppoſe, that ſhe can have had thoſe Notices from them; it muſt follow, that ſhe muſt either have receiv'd, what ſhe has deliver'd, from the ſame Hand as they did, or elſe that ſhe muſt have been inſtructed by One, that was perfectly skill'd in their Writings; to believe which, we have nothing but ſimple Conjecture, againſt many Reaſons to the contrary. Therefore if the Authority of the one be good, the Authority of the other muſt be ſo too: And we cannot Deny <hi>one,</hi> but we muſt Deny <hi>both.</hi> Beſides, if there be not only with all the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets
<pb facs="tcp:38278:15"/>
of the People of God, but alſo with ſeveral others who were Stran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers to his Written Law, an Harmony as to the Main Things contain'd in This Book, concerning the Glorious Days of the Future Golden Period, the Authority is ſtill ſtronger: And if the Conſent be remarkable in ſome leſs heeded Particulars, it is yet more won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derful, and not to be ſlighted. And tho' they all ſhould have been no more Sanctified or Regenerated than <hi>Balaam,</hi> and ſhould have Propheſy'd no other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe than He, or <hi>Caiaphas,</hi> it's ſo far from weakening, that it ſtrengthens their Evidence: In as much as the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vourable Teſtimony of an Enemy goes beyond that of a Friend. Further ſtill, if in the ſame Time, at very di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant Places, there has been found to be, as by Letters from <hi>Switzerland,</hi> and other remote Parts has been wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs'd, ſuch an Agreement as could not poſſibly proceed, but either from a Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine or Humane Communication; and there be all the Marks of the One, and none at all of the Other, it's a mighty
<pb facs="tcp:38278:16"/>
Confirmation, and we cannot, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the higheſt Affront to that Reaſon which we pretend ſo much to, but give it to that ſide which has all the real Characters of Truth and Sincerity, when the other has only Phanſies and Suſpicions to ſupport its Credit.</p>
            <p>But if beſides all this, God himſelf has been pleas'd by his Immediate Fin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger to ſet his Seal to the Truth of theſe <hi>Revelations,</hi> and to confirm 'em in a Miraculous Manner, as will <hi>in part</hi> ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear by the Account of ſome Matters of Fact nakedly related in This <hi>Letter,</hi> that are evidently above the Power of Nature; then one would think there could be no longer any room for ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out againſt, or even for not ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rendring one ſelf up to, the Belief of their Divine Original. And if all the Marks of True Inſpiration be Appli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cable to Theſe, and no Objection has been made to 'em, which has not been made to thoſe of the Acknowledg'd Prophets, in the Times wherein they liv'd; as might be inſtanc'd at large: I know not what more can be deſir'd.
<pb facs="tcp:38278:16"/>
This is left to the Spirits of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets, and to the Conſideration of all thoſe, who profeſs to believe that <hi>ſure Word of Propheſie,</hi> which is the <hi>Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony of JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Many Teſtimonies relating to this Matter might eaſily be brought, were it either Needful, or Convenient, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the preſent Circumſtances ſo to do. Whence it is thought fit to Publiſh on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly One, that has been Communicated by an Eye and Ear-witneſs, who made it his Buſineſs to be perfectly acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted with this Matter. By all which, and by a mighty Cloud, who daily bear Teſtimony hereto, and eſpecially by the Two Witneſſes of the Old and New Teſtament, there are ſome, who for their own parts dare ſay, that they are fully Convinc'd, both as to the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velations conſider'd apart, and as to the Bleſſed Lady, whom God has cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen to be the Inſtrument of 'em. Who is not in the decreaſe at all, but ſtill gloriouſly proceeds, as is well known to many, in the Increaſe of this Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellous
<pb facs="tcp:38278:17"/>
Illumination. The Sun-beams of the Divine Light and Glory, do every day more Throughly, and more Intimately Enlighten, the Bright Wounds of Jeſus do daily more and more purifie Her; and in ſhort, ſhe is in ſuch a manner prepar'd, that if She be call'd out hereafter, of the Solitude in which ſhe is at preſent, and be Crown'd with Glory, Wiſdom and Power, it will be no more than what we may reaſonably expect.</p>
            <p>It is not to be doubted, but that the Spirit will bear Witneſs that this is Truth, to all that will liſten to it in the pure ſtilneſs of <hi>Holy Silence.</hi> And I am well aſſur'd, that here in <hi>England,</hi> in like manner as it has done in <hi>Germa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny</hi> and <hi>Holland,</hi> it muſt work with great Power on the Souls of many; and that God will do ſomething in a little time, to awaken the Slumbering Nations.</p>
            <p>But granting there ſhould be nothing at all Divine in this Matter, I can't ſee
<pb facs="tcp:38278:17"/>
any Hurt, that the Publiſhing of it to this Nation would be. For here is no Encouragement to any Frantick Zeal, to ſet up it ſelf in the Name of the Lord; nothing to promote Seditions, Strifes and Diſſentions, but the quite contrary; nothing for the Eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a Sect or Party, but frequent and powerful Incitements to Peace, Unity and Love of every one: Nothing taught, but what is highly Agreeable to the Doctrine of Chriſt; and nothing Foretold, which a Good Man may not wiſh for, or which, as to the Main, is not publickly Pray'd for, in Moſt, or All the Congregations of Any that are call'd Chriſtians: In ſome of 'em Oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>caſionally, in others Conſtantly: As the Converſion of the <hi>Jews,</hi> the Ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> the Deſtruction of all Idolatry, Superſtition, Hereſie and Schiſm, the Settlement of Peace, Truth and Righteouſneſs, over the whole Earth; that ſo all that <hi>will</hi> may come to be Enlighten'd, and thoſe that <hi>will not,</hi> but obſtinately refuſe the Light, may be caſt out into the outward Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs;
<pb facs="tcp:38278:18"/>
the Kingdoms of this World be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing made the Kingdom of our God, and of his Chriſt, and there being One Fold, under One Shepherd. If then theſe things be in themſelves deſirable, and to be Pray'd for, and have been Pray'd for above theſe Sixteen Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Years; we muſt needs allow, that there can't be any Hurt in the Belief of 'em to be near at hand: And conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently, let this Matter of Fact be ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſo conteſtible, it can have no Bad Influence, either upon the Lives and Actions of Any, or upon Publick Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fairs. But if this Matter be indeed of God, God will go along with it Here, and thoſe that Fight againſt it, will be found to Fight againſt God. So that if it be of Him, it ſhall ſtand, and Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>umph; and if it be <hi>not</hi> of Him, none can more Earneſtly deſire that it may come to Nothing, than He who ſends it Now abroad to the <hi>Engliſh</hi> Nation, for this End, that God alone may be Glorify'd, and that Truth and Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſnes may Prevail, to the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſion of Errour and Impiety. To
<pb facs="tcp:38278:18" rendition="simple:additions"/>
which let all the Earth ſay <hi>Amen. Hallelujah.</hi>
            </p>
            <epigraph>
               <q>
                  <l>Come Holy Ghoſt, our Souls inſpire,</l>
                  <l>And lighten with Celeſtial Fire:</l>
                  <l>Thou the Anointing Spirit, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
            </epigraph>
         </div>
         <div type="part">
            <head>[Form of Ordering of Prieſts.]</head>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>1 Theſ. v. 19, 20, 21.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>Quench not the Spirit. Deſpiſe not Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſyings. Prove all things: hold faſt that which is Good.</p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>Acts xxii. 14, 15.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>The God of our Fathers hath choſen Thee, that thou ſhouldeſt know his Will, and ſee that Juſt One, and ſhouldeſt hear the Voice of his Mouth: for thou ſhalt be his Witneſs unto all Men, of what thou haſt Seen and Heard.</p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>John xiv. 21.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>He that loveth me, ſhall be loved of my Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and I will love him, and will manifeſt my ſelf to him.</p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <pb facs="tcp:38278:19" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <hi>1 Cor. ii. 10, 11, 12, 13.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>God hath Revealed them to us by his Spirit; for the Spirit ſearcheth all things, yea the deep things of God. For who knows the things of a Man ſave the Spirit of a Man? even ſo the things of God knows none but the Spirit of God. Now we have received not the Spirit of the World [or <hi>of Man,</hi>] but the Spirit of God; that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God. Which alſo we ſpeak, not in the words which Man's wiſdom teacheth, but which the Holy Ghoſt teacheth; comparing Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual things with Spiritual.</p>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>And afterward v. 14, 15.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>But the Natural <hi>(the Animal, or Souliſh)</hi> Man receives not the things of the Spirit of God: For they are fooliſhneſs to him; neither can ye know them, becauſe they are ſpiritually diſcer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned. But he that is Spiritual diſcerneth all things, yet he himſelf is diſcerned of no Man.</p>
            </q>
            <q>
               <bibl>
                  <hi>John i. 46.</hi>
               </bibl>
               <p>Can there any good thing come out of <hi>Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zareth?</hi>—Come, and ſee.</p>
            </q>
         </div>
         <div xml:lang="lat" type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:19"/>
            <head>The Teſtimony which is referr'd to in the Preface.</head>
            <p>EST illa Virgo ſingularibus &amp; ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>xime ſupernaturalibus a Deo or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nata donis Spiritus, ita ut externus ip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſius faciei habitus, cum intima animae &amp; Spiritus qualitate ſuaviter reſponde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>at. Gaudet mirabili, &amp; ſumme extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinaria a Deo vocatione, ita ut ſi curriculum Vitae ipſius attente, &amp; cum cura perlegeris, ad plane ſingularia ip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſam a Deo electam &amp; co-ordinatam eſſe fateberis. In externa converſatione adverſus omnes tam amicos, quam ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>micos praeprimis eminet blanda ejus cum intima humilitate conjuncta gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vitas. Et cum multa tela a Satana ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctenus experta, animus ejus in tam quietum, &amp; tranquillum gaudii &amp; pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cis intimae ſtatum eſt deductus, ita ut veluti infans nihil magis anhelet, quam ut incorrupto &amp; continuo nexu in opti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mi Patris voluntate, tanquam in tutiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſimis Spiritus Tabernaculis ſuaviter ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quieſcere
<pb facs="tcp:38278:20"/>
poſſit. Quod ſi ſpectes ipſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>us <hi>Revelationes,</hi> ſunt quaſi compendi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>um illarum rerum quae in Eccleſia <hi>Sioni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tica,</hi> &amp; hoc, &amp; futuro tempore ſint proditura in publicum Mundi Thea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trum: Alias illae ſunt ex fonte vivo, eſſentiali petitae, &amp; profundiſſimae, ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hilominus tamen primitiae tantum eo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rum quae ſua aetate majori cum abun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dantia manifeſtabuntur. Pondus, Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſtatem, &amp; cum <gap reason="foreign">
                  <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
               </gap> conjun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctam Divinitatem harum Revelatio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num in ipſa lectione, ſi praemeditatis precibus eam fueris aggreſſus, ſenties. Nec eſt quod cogites ipſam vel ex libro, vel alio rerum divinarum perito, tan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tam, tamque profundam hauſiſſe ſapi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>entiam, ſed ex Simplici, Majeſtatico, &amp; plane Prophetico Stylo, imo ex ipſa impletionis experientia, ipſam a Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tu Sancto eſſentialiter fuiſſe edoctam certo certius tibi affirmare poteris. Hinc eſt, quod earundem prima publi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>catio in Lingua <hi>Germanica,</hi> non ſine larga benedictionis meſſe hactenus fue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit: cum alii honoribus &amp; rebus mun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>danis impliciti ex harum lectione, ſi
<pb facs="tcp:38278:20"/>
non penitus mutati, tamen ad magis ſeriam circa Chriſtianiſmum ſumme neceſſariam impendendam curam, &amp; ſolicitudinem quam maxime ſunt inſtigati: Alii correpti jam tum a Deo, &amp; in dulciſſimo Servatore per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formati, inter legendum ex laetiſſimo harum Revelationum nuncio ad dul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciſſimi Vini Spiritualis perceptionem, &amp; gaudii, Celeſtis ſenſus ſunt deducti: Alii Divinitatem harum Revelationum deſtruendi &amp; evertendi molitores con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſi, &amp; ad ſilentium redacti: Alii a contemptu, reprehenſione, &amp; refuta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tione harum Revelationum divinitus avocati &amp; repreſſi, ut ita facile pateat, quod Teſtimoniorum circa harum Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velationum cumulus, neque hoc, ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>que futuro Tempore, unquam tibi de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſſe poterit. Quare ne quaeſo illotis Revelationum harum lectionem ag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grediare manibus, neque praeoccupatis judiciis, &amp; corruptae rationis ſcrupulis eas laceres; ſed cogita ſpiritualia ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritualiter eſſe dijudicanda. Laboran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dum hinc tibi praeprimis eſt, &amp; oran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dum, ut eo, ex quo hauſtae ſunt Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lationes,
<pb facs="tcp:38278:21"/>
Spiritu; &amp; vero ſecundum harum Revelationum Mentem tuam conformandi propoſito, polleas. Quo ſi fueris inſtructus, &amp; vere correptus a Domino, non (ſecundum Spiritus ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepti, &amp; illuminationis menſuram) tantum Divinitatem harum Revelatio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num recte dijudicaveris, ſed &amp; bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictio largiſſima, incrementum agni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tionis vivificae ſingulare, &amp; gaudium a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moris &amp; pacis Divinae in Te redunda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bit certiſſimum &amp; uberrimum. Vale, &amp; prout gloria Dei requirit utere hiſce, ſalutariter, &amp; feliciter.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>S. D. G.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:38278:21"/>
            <head>The ſame in Engliſh.</head>
            <p>THis Virgin is endow'd by God, with Singular and very Supernatural Gifts of the Spirit, ſo as even her out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Air and Countenance, do ſweetly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpire with the Inward Qualifications ofher Soul and Spirit. She has obtain'd a Wonderful and moſt Extraordinary Call from God; ſo that if thou read her Life with Attention and Care, thou ſhalt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs, that ſhe is by God Choſen and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dain'd for Matters altogether Singular. In her outward Converſation with all, both Friends and Enemies, but more eſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cially with theſe, there ſhines forth in Her a pleaſant Gravity, in Conjunction with the deepeſt Humility. And tho' hitherto ſhe has experienc'd many of <hi>Satan</hi>'s Darts, her Mind is brought into ſuch a quiet and still State of Joy and Peace within, that like a little Child, ſhe breathes after no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing more, than that ſhe may without Mixture, and without Interruption, ſweetly reſt in the Will of her most kind
<pb facs="tcp:38278:22"/>
Father, as in the ſecureſt Tabernacle for her Spirit to dwell in. Now if you look to Her <hi>Revelations,</hi> they are as it were an Abridgment of thoſe Things, which in the <hi>SION</hi>-Church are to be brought forth, both in This, and in the Next Age, upon the Publick Theatre of the World. Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides they are taken from the very Living and Eſſential Fountain, and are moſt Deep; nevertheleſs they are but the Firſt Fruits of thoſe, which ſhall in greater a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bundance be publiſh'd in their proper Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon. The Weight, the Majeſty, the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venlineſs, and the Inſpiration of theſe <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velations,</hi> you will feel in the very Read<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of them, if with due Preparation of Prayer, you ſet about it. And think not, that either from any Book, or from any Perſon skill'd in Divine Matters, ſhe has fetch'd this ſo great, and ſo profound a Wiſdom that is in them: But from their Plain, Majeſtick, and perfectly Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical Style; yea, from the very Experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence of their Fulfilling, you may with the greateſt Certainty maintain, that ſhe is Eſſentially taught by God. Hence it is, that the Firſt Publiſhing of 'em in the
<pb facs="tcp:38278:22"/>
               <hi>German</hi> Tongue, has not hitherto been without a large Harveſt of Bleſſing; ſince ſome involv'd in the Honours and Affairs of the World, have been, by the Reading of 'em, if not <hi>wholly</hi> chang'd, yet moſt mightily ſtir'd up <hi>at leaſt,</hi> to the exerting a more ſerious Care and Watchfulneſs a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout the <hi>Chriſtian</hi> Religion, of the great Neceſſity of which they are made ſenſible: Others being even then Convinc'd by God, and perfectly Transform'd in their moſt ſweet Saviour, have by the moſt Joyful Tidings of theſe Revelations, been Tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ported, as they were Read, to taſte the moſt delicious Wine of the Spirit, and to have a Senſe of the Joy of Heaven. O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers who have labour'd to deſtroy, and o'rethrow the Divine Authority of theſe <hi>Revelations,</hi> have been Confounded, and put to Silence: Others have been in a Miraculous Manner recall'd, and withheld from the Contempt, Cenſure and Refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of 'em. From all which it may eaſily appear, that a Cloud of Witneſſes, both in the Preſent and Future Age, will never be wanting to confirm their Autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity. Wherefore ſet not about, I beſeech
<pb facs="tcp:38278:23"/>
you, the Reading of Theſe <hi>Revelations,</hi> with unwaſh'd Hands, neither ſuffer 'em to be Tortur'd with Pre-conceiv'd Noti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, or the Scruples of Corrupted Reaſon, but conſider, that Spiritual Things are to be Spiritually diſcern'd. Hence above all, you are to Labour, and Pray, that you may be endued with the ſame Spirit from which They do proceed, and with a Real Purpoſe of Conforming your Mind accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the Practice of 'em. Which when you ſhall have obtain'd, and ſhall be truly Convinc'd of the Lord, then you ſhall, (according to that meaſure of the Spirit and Light which you have receiv'd) not only be able to judge Rightly concerning the Divine Original of Theſe <hi>Revelati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons;</hi> but there ſhall alſo a moſt large Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing, a ſingular Encreaſe of Living Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, and a most certain, and moſt plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiful Enjoyment of the Love, and of the Peace of God, flow down upon you in a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bundance. Farewel; and as the Glory of God requires, uſe Them to your Salvati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and Happineſs.</p>
            <closer>Glory be to God Alone.</closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:38278:23" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A LETTER To Some DIVINES,</hi> Whether God doth any more reveal him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf by the means of Divine Appari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, <hi>&amp;c?</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">Grace, Peace, Light and Wiſdom, from God the FATHER, through JESUS CHRIST our Lord.</head>
            <head type="sub">
               <hi>Right Reverend and Worthy Fathers and Brethren in Chriſt.</hi>
            </head>
            <div type="part">
               <head>I.</head>
               <p>SInce God in theſe our Times has done great Things on a young Lady, worthy of admiration to all the World;
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:38278:24"/>
therefore thought I my ſelf obliged in Conſcience to give you a Relation of this Matter as exact as is poſſible, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſting you to impart to me what you ſhall judge of this Affair, as Chriſtians, and in the Fear of God. And indeed the Worth and Excellence of the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject requires that you refuſe me not this Favour.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>II.</head>
               <p>A Daughter of a very Honoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Family was Born in the Year MDCLXXII. in the Month of <hi>No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vember,</hi> who is now Nineteen Years old, the Seventh Child of her Parents; who from her Infancy has been of a good Humour, having neither Melan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>choly, nor Subtilty in her Temper, as all thoſe can witneſs who have conver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed with her: Who muſt grant that there is in her ſomething that is Inno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cent without any diſguiſe, and that there needs no more but only to look on her, to perceive ſomething that cannot be expreſſed of Great and Singular in her very Face. Notwithſtanding theſe high Qualities ſhe is yet ſo Humble and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:38278:24"/>
Submiſſive, as if ſhe had them not: She Sacrifices them all to Him from whom ſhe has receiv'd them, and to whom alone that Honour is due; ſo that I am bold to ſay in the Preſence of God, that I have never ſeen ſo Humble an Heart endow'd with ſo rare Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fections, and I believe the Ages which are paſt can hardly bring a Parallel.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>III.</head>
               <p>As ſhe was Seven Years old, without having ever pray'd for any ſuch high Matters, ſhe received from God a moſt Particular Favour. One day being with her Mother, who then according to her Cuſtom, made her Family to perform their common Devotions, ſhe ſaw in the midſt of her Prayer, a Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon clad all in Glory, and of moſt won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derful Beauty, making up towards her with a great deal of kindneſs; who had a Golden Shield before his Breaſt, and whoſe Face was full of Light. This ſhe diſcover'd the very ſame mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to her Elder Siſter, who not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>garding it, let it paſs.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:38278:25"/>
               <head>IV.</head>
               <p>After which this lovely Converſati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of her Saviour encreaſing according as ſhe advanced in Years, it fell out that one day at Dinner, her Siſters telling one another, in the preſence of their Mother, what they had Dream'd the Night before, ſhe ſaid to them, that ſhe indeed had not any Dreams at all, but that the Saviour of the World, wh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>om ſhe beheld to regard her with a very gracious look, had in this wiſe expreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſpoken to her: <hi>I am JES<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>S CHRIST, who am wounded for thee: I will betroth my ſelf to thee for evermore, and will remain thy Bridegroom:</hi> Adding, that after this he had promis'd to ſend her his Angel to gather up her Tears, when ſhe ſhould be Afflicted. Which punctually came to paſs, when weep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing one time for the grief which a Fit of a Feaver had cauſed, ſhe ſaw an Angel gathering up her Tears in a Golden Vial, with a Conceit of moſt Majeſtick Muſick, which ſtruck her Ears, being for certain all the while Awake.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:38278:25"/>
               <head>V.</head>
               <p>This happened about her Ninth Year, but in the following Years the Lord manifeſted himſelf to her ſtill more Gloriouſly every day. For one time as ſhe was according to her Cuſtom before God in Prayer, ſhe perceiv'd an Hand to be laid upon her Head, and this Voice uttered, <hi>Caſt thy Burthen upon the Lord: Hope in him, and he ſhall do thee good.</hi> She receiv'd theſe Words in Faith, which prov'd to her afterward a Sure Comfort on all Occaſions.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>VI.</head>
               <p>A little while after this, being all a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lone in her Prayer, ſhe ſaw again the ſame Perſon that ſhe had ſeen before, but in greater Majeſty and Glory, draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing near to her as if it were to embrace her. It is true that at the firſt this gave her ſome little Dread, but He the Savi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our, who is the ſtrength of the weak, did in ſuch wiſe ſtrengthen her, that her Spirit being quite fill'd with Love, all Fear was driven out.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:38278:26"/>
               <head>VII.</head>
               <p>When ſhe was now about Twelve Years old, the Lord ſhewed her the whole Courſe, or Repreſentation, of his Paſſion; in like manner as it had been exhibited in the Year MDCXXV. to <hi>Chriſtiern</hi> IV. King of <hi>Denmark,</hi> in the Caſtle of <hi>Roſenbourg.</hi> She had alſo beſides this about the ſame time many Divine Openings and Revelations of mighty Importance; which at preſent cannot be here all particulariz'd. But this is not to be omitted, that ſhe once appeared to her ſelf to be cloathed in a white Robe, and to become very great: And many Stars in the Heavens ſhe be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>held caſting their Rays upon her Body, by which means it was rendred very Luminous and Glorious. Now asking the Lord what might be the meaning of all this, ſhe receiv'd for an Anſwer, that theſe were only Glances of his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to her. At the ſame time ſhe heard a Voice above the Clouds, which repeated three ſeveral times theſe words, <hi>Fear God, and keep his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandments: Fear God, and keep his Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandments:
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:38278:26"/>
Let all the World fear God, and keep his Commandments.</hi> This be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ended, ſhe ſaw CHRIST ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rounded with a great multitude of Saints, in white Robes, and Crowns of Gold on their Heads, which they took off, and caſt at his Feet, and proſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting themſelves ſung: <hi>To thee, O Lamb of God, be the honour and the praiſe for ever and ever.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>VIII.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>This lovely and ſweet Saviour pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented himſelf once to her, ſaying,</hi> Be not afraid, Thou art my Love, my Fair one, my Deareſt, my Queen; and I am thy Friend, thy King, and Shepherd, I will not forſake thee, nor neglect thee: Be at rest, and fear nothing, I ſtrengthen thee, and uphold thee, I will not take away that which I have given thee: For hereto I have ordained thee from all Eternity. <hi>HE alſo at other times witneſs'd the ſame to others, whom ſhe was oblig'd to write to in theſe words:</hi> I am revealed in the Spirit to a Maid, whoſe Mother is a Widow.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:38278:27"/>
               <head>IX.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>Another time JESUS CHRIST ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared to her in this manner: His Blood ſparkling like Rubies ran down from his moſt holy Head, the little Wounds in his Face being laid open glitter'd ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry much, from his Hands and Feet ſtream'd forth bright Blood, and a ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſhining Chryſtalline Water. HE ſpoke to her theſe words, which ſhe noted down at that very time:</hi> Come my Dove, and rest in my Heart; for my Heart is thy Chamber to ſleep in, and my Wounds thy Bed to rest in: My Life is thine, my Glory is thine: I am thine, and will remain thine. <hi>Again HE ſaid,</hi> Walk before me and be good: Serve me faithful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and follow me, I will enflame thy Heart with a lively burning Devotion, and with the Light of my Grace. Thy Prayers ſhall be as perfume before me, and I will anſwer them. Thou art my dear Child, my pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Child, my moſt lovely Child; and I am thy God, thy Fortreſs; thy Life, and thy Light.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:38278:27"/>
               <head>X.</head>
               <p>As this bleſſed Creature was fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd with theſe, and many other, Refreſhments by CHRIST her Well-beloved, ſhe was at the ſame time ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed, like S. <hi>Paul,</hi> to the pinchings and buffettings of the Devil. For at di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe times ſhe has ſeen in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ll day Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tan preſent himſelf before her, in the ſhape of a Black, with b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3+ letters">
                     <desc>•••…</desc>
                  </gap>ng Eyes, and an horrible Face, being attended with other Devils, who together with him endeavouring to lay word on her, were not able; but after having a little terrify'd her, were driven away by the holy Angels, whom God had ſent for her defence and reſcue. A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3+ letters">
                     <desc>•••…</desc>
                  </gap> the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vil appear'd to her one day with a Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fin, making a ſhew of caſting her into it, when no ſooner had ſhe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3+ letters">
                     <desc>•••…</desc>
                  </gap>'d upon God to help her, by ſaying <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>herefore is the Son of God revealed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy the Works of the</hi> De<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                     <desc>••…</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> at theſe words became as ſo m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> flaming Scourges, which were <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> to her Eyes, and forced the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ave her.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:38278:28"/>
               <head>XI.</head>
               <p>In the ſame Year it pleas'd the Great GOD, to give her an Opening out of the holy <hi>Revelation,</hi> eſpecially out of the xxth and xxiſt of the ſaid Book: Which I here ſubjoin, that you may judge, whether it be poſſible that this could be produced by the Phanſy, or by any Faculty of the Soul in a Child ſo young as this. The Manifeſtations which the LORD dictated <hi>Verbatim,</hi> and g<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                     <desc>••…</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> her Pen in ſetting down, when ſhe was hardly able to Write or Spell, and which ſhe keeps by her in the Original, are theſe word for word: <q>I will go forth within a little while, and will bind the Devil in ſuch a man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, that he ſhall not be able to fly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny more in the Air, nor to ſeduce Mankind<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and then I will come upon the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> God and Man, with the holy C<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                        <desc>••…</desc>
                     </gap> JERUALEM, and will Judge <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 words">
                        <desc>〈◊◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> I will, and my dear Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtians <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> appoint Judges, and my Glory <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                        <desc>••…</desc>
                     </gap>nd them, and in my Br<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                        <desc>••…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> they ſhine. I will giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                        <desc>••…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> Power to Teach and
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:38278:28"/>
to Reprove; and I will give them ſuch a Spirit as I have given to thoſe who are Beheaded for my Name. Such a Spirit ſhall reſt double upon all of them, and they ſhall reign with me a Thouſand Years, and I will give them great power to bring in the Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norant; that ſo there may be one Shepherd, and one Fold. The Wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Dead ſhall not live again till the Thouſand Years be expired, and then they ſhall be raiſed to Judgment. So ſhall all the Bleſſed be in the Kingdom, and I will deſcend with all the Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful and Elect Souls, and will keep Heaven as it were with the Children of Men. I will alſo preſerve Chriſtia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity for a Thouſand Years, ſo as it may during that time <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3+ letters">
                        <desc>•••…</desc>
                     </gap>eaſe, till that the Number be <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>. When therefore theſe Thouſand Years ſhall be finiſhed, I will be no longer with <hi>Chriſtendom,</hi> after th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                        <desc>••…</desc>
                     </gap>nner; but will go unto the Father into the wide Eternity, together with the Elect, leaving here the <hi>JER<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>SALEM-Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stendom:</hi> And I will <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Satan to
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:38278:29"/>
come forth, that he may ſeduce the People that are hardned, which ſhall remain, which are <hi>Gog</hi> and <hi>Magog.</hi> And theſe ſhall be gathered together in Battel againſt the Chriſtians, who are my holy People. But I will then cauſe Fire to fall from Heaven, and will de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy them utterly, and bring them to an End: And I will raiſe all the Dead, and will make an end of this World, and the Faithful who ſhall then be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>live, I will transform, and will ſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tence the Good and the Wicked.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XII.</head>
               <p>As now her Mother ſaw and read ſo many Revelations, ſhe became impati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent to be ſatisfied whence they did pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed, and being of the Opinion that ſhe could not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> than to impart the ſame to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3+ letters">
                     <desc>•••…</desc>
                  </gap>eſſor, ſhe took this Reſolution <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> diſcover'd to him the whole Affa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> he exhorted her to ſtand upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2+ letters">
                     <desc>••…</desc>
                  </gap>ard, conſidering how the Devil could transform himſelf into an Angel of Light; and other like Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices he gave her. As therefore the Mother with her Daughters were trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:38278:29"/>
at this, and in great Affliction throwing themſelves on their Knees before Chriſt, pray'd him, that he would reveal to them, whether that which the Prieſt had ſaid was true, or whether it was he himſelf the true Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viour, JESUS CHRIST, the Son of the Living God, who had overcome the Devil, and bruis'd the Serpent's Head? And in caſe it were He who had hither<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to appear'd to this Child, that he would continue to ſpeak to her as before: But if not, that he would put the Devil to ſilence.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XIII.</head>
               <p>Then the Kind Saviour accepting their Prayer, made Anſwer in this wiſe, <q>I am the Son of God who have bruiſed the Head of the Serpent, and not he who ſeduced <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> in the form of an<note n="*" place="margin">This agrees with <hi>Patrick</hi>'s Annot. <hi>Gen. c.</hi> 3.</note> Angel of Light. I do not Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel what is good againſt my own Will, as doth Satan. I who ſpeak with you am that God who governeth and reigneth over the Cherubim and the Seraphim. But
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:38278:30"/>
I ſee your weak Faith, how you wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, and ſuffer your ſelves to be ſha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken by a little Guſt: However I have patience with you, and will make you mine Elect ones in the Furnace of Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bulation. And what I have begun thus meanly, I will gloriouſly accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh: Whereas Satan beginneth al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways gloriouſly, and endeth piti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XIV.</head>
               <p>HE alſo ſaid, <q>Many Preachers who ought to enlarge the Gates that I the King of Glory ſhould come in, do ſtop them up; wherefore theſe not being worthy, I will chuſe my ſelf ſome who ſhall do this in the Joy of their Hearts. I tell you now, I the SON of God, who have choſen you out to be my People, and Heritage, that I will make you undoubted Heirs in the Kingdom of my FATHER, and will exalt you very high for evermore. I have now eſtabliſhed you faſt by means of my faithful Temptation; for ye may at this time well believe that I
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:38278:30"/>
am the true CHRIST, from whom the Devils fly away.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XV.</head>
               <p>She after this, ſaw CHRIST in the Clouds, ſpeaking theſe Words: <q>Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold, I march upon the wings of the Wind, the Lord of Hoſts is my Name. I am the God of <hi>Abraham,</hi> of <hi>Iſaac,</hi> and of <hi>Jacob;</hi> and alſo your God too, who will make you come forth to my Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. Therefore be not faint in the Faith; for I will avenge mine Honour with a mighty hand, and will not keep ſilence in my Cauſe.</q> Moreover ſhe ſaw God the Father, in Heaven, ſeated upon an high Throne, in Raiment white as Snow, with a goodly Crown on his Head, having in one hand a Scep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, and in the other a Sword: Who ſpoke thus: <q>Look on me, I am the Husband of all Widows, and the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of all Orphans: I will judge their right, for I know it; for their miſery is come up before me, and nothing is hidden from me. Wherefore Afflict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt thou thy ſelf? Caſt thy Confidence upon me: For I will viſit the Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:38278:31"/>
of <hi>Sion,</hi> and the Sackcloth that is upon her, I will take off, and the Aſhes that cover her head I will throw away, and will anoint her head with the Oyl of gladneſs. I will cure her Wounds, and bind up her Sores. Mine Arm ſhall become ſtrong: For I am reſolved to help her, and to place her upon Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lars of Marble. She ſhall be ſet upon a Pedeſtal of Gold, and ſhall Triumph even in this Age. Her Countenance ſhall be bright, and her Heart fill'd with Mirth, and her Victory ſhall laſt to the Children, and Childrens Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren. And think not that this ſhall be long before it come to paſs. See! behold! thou knoweſt not as I know! The time is not long! The time is not long!</q> Then alſo an Angel ſounded with his Trumpet theſe words, <hi>The time is not long.</hi> After that ſhe had ſeen God the FATHER in the Clouds, whoſe Face ſhe could well diſtinguiſh, ſhe was thereupon wholy carried out of her ſelf, and heard theſe words: <q>I am your God, and you are the Sheep of my Paſture: You are my People
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:38278:31"/>
which I have choſen before many Thouſand; my Glory ſhall be ſud<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>denly Publiſhed: For this end remain ſtedfaſt in the Faith.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XVI.</head>
               <p>This paſſ'd in the Fifteenth year of her Age, and from that time to this preſent day, our Saviour has been pleaſ'd to manifeſt himſelf very gloriouſly to her and by her, and has confirm'd her in her Soul, and fully Aſſur'd her, that this was not from Melancholy, or the Devil; but that it was the Son of God himſelf, who ſpoke with her, as one Friend ſpeaks with another Friend. And ſhe firmly believes that God has determin'd ſome great matter over the World, that he will ſhew his mercy to his Servants, and his wrath to his Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies, and will bring forth his SION to the Aſtoniſhment of the whole Earth. I will produce here ſome of thoſe Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monies, or Divine Manifeſtations, which, amongſt ſeveral Hundred, have been given ſince the Year MDCXXXVIII. to this preſent MDCXCI. from the riches of his Mercy to Mankind.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:38278:32"/>
               <head>XVII.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi rend="margQuotes">In that which follows, HE ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſts forth his holy Love towards his Well-beloved ones, by aſſuring them that he will free them from the burden of the Croſs, and do ſomething great in their behalf.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Deareſt Souls, behold, I beſeech you, in what manner my Soul longs and pants after you, that your Souls may be one with me, that we may become one Heart, one Spirit, one Soul. For I de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire to dwell in you, to govern in you, to work in you, whom I have always loved, whom I have drawn to me, and for whom I have deliver'd up my ſelf to the Death, being made for you a ſacrifice of Propitiation. Wherefore ſhould I not then love you, after that you are thus made righteous by my Blood? And therefore lift up your heads, rejoyce, cry aloud, and Sing with a mighty Noiſe; for he who hath deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered you from everlaſting Death, and ſhall deliver you from the burthen of the Croſs, even he will paſs before you in Glory and perform great things for
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:38278:32"/>
you. For I am the Lord, and who ſhall hinder me? Who ſhall ſay to me, What doſt thou? Am I not the God of <hi>Abraham, Iſaac</hi> and <hi>Jacob,</hi> a Powerful Lord over Sin, Death, the Devil, and Hell.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi rend="margQuotes">The Bridegroom aſſures his Bride, that ſhe being cloathed with his Righteouſneſs, and with the Garments of Salvation, is well pleaſing to the Father for His ſake.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>My Love, thou fair one, thou love<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and charming Shepherdeſs, how ami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able art thou in my Heavenly Father's Sight, then when I am united with thee, then when I put on thee my righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs as a Robe, and adorn thee with the Gold-work of Faith, and Gird thee with the Girdle of Truth, and Crown thee with the Palm-Branches of Praiſe! O art thou not then indeed a beautiful Shepherdeſs! O how lovely, how charming art thou among the Thorns! Thine Eyes have overcome me, their Rays have wounded my heart; for as the fair Morning Star they
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:38278:33"/>
Sparkle, and are more glittering then the goodlieſt Splendour. For in them ſhine forth the works that are the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light of my Soul. Now in all that is ſacred nothing can be loved, but what is without all ſpot and blame. And now therefore, my ſweet Shepherdeſs, ſince thou appeareſt ſo comely in the Garments of Salvatiton, thou art not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly well pleaſing to my Father, but alſo to me, thy Shepherd, thy Companion, thy Bridegroom, thy Brother, and thy moſt truſty and faſt Friend, who ſhall love thee, and cheriſh thee for all E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ternity.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="3">
                  <hi rend="margQuotes">3. The King tells the Daughter of <hi>Sion,</hi> that her Guilt of Blood ſhall be taken from her, and that ſhe ſhall be deliver'd out of Captivity.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>All Hail, Dear Friends, rejoice ye, and be glad; for the happy Day com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth, that is prepared for you: Yea the Hour cometh, in which I approach more near to you, and in which I fill you with Joy. The time is come that I glorify thee the Daughter of SION,
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:38278:33"/>
and make thee again, O Virgin, to be Holy. For thou, O <hi>Iſrael,</hi> art hitherto gone aſtray and art blind: Neverthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs thy Sight ſhall be reſtored to thee, when that Innocent Blood, which thou haſt pulled down upon thy ſelf, and upon thy Children, ſhall be taken off. But now I ſay unto you: Be merry O Daughter of SION; for I will bring thee forth out of the Priſon of Tribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, and thy Wounds I will cleanſe, and will dreſs them with the Oyl of Grace; with the ſweet heavenly Uncti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on I will anoint thee, and thou ſhalt know that I am thy God who have Created thee, redeemed thee, and ſanctified thee.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi rend="margQuotes">HE aſſures her that the Joyful Viſitation of Grace will come, when her Warfare ſhall be finiſhed, and the time of her Reprobation paſſed over.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Thou <hi>Ephraim</hi> my Elect, fear not; for I am with thee: Quit not the Faith, for I am thy God. Be Vigilant and Slumber not, for behold there cometh the time of the Viſitation, in which I
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:38278:34"/>
will make Roſes to grow upon the dry Thorns of affliction; and in which I will again moiſten the dead Trunk, that it may ſprout forth, and ſpread it ſelf as the King's Crown, be pleaſant to the Eye as the Lilly, white as the Snow, ſplendid as Juſtice in her Pomp. The time of Deſolation is paſſed over: Upon thee, O Daughter, ſhall Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments be put as at the firſt, and thy Rags ſhall be taken from thee, thine Head ſhall be anointed with Oil, and the Veil of thy Virginity ſhall be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtored again to thee; thou ſhalt put off Mourning, thou ſhalt be led out of the Path of Affliction, and upon thy Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head ſhall be ſet Palms of Praiſe; ſo that thou ſhalt rejoice, as a Bird that is eſcaped from the hands of the Fowler. Thus ſhall it be done to thee, O Daughter of <hi>Sion.</hi>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi rend="margQuotes">HE alſo foretells, how the <hi>Edo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mites,</hi> for being the Enemies of the <hi>Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raelits</hi> ſhall be puniſhed; when at the ſame time it ſhall go well with <hi>Sion,</hi> and ſhe ſhall be ſet off in the fineſt Gold.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>
                     <pb n="23" facs="tcp:38278:34"/>Mine heart is full of Kindneſs and Love: And that yours may be in like manner ſo, joyn your ſelves unto me, ſo ſhall ye be made Perfect. Be ye Friendly, ſhewing kindneſs towards all Men; ſo ſhall ye be well pleaſing to me. Daughter of SION, I have now covered thy Face, ſo that thou art forced to ſit as a Blind beggar by the Way-ſide, and to be trod upon by all the World, as her at whom all People are aſhamed, and thy Relations are like the Children of <hi>Edom.</hi> But be glad, O my Daughter of <hi>Sion,</hi> it ſhall be well with thee again. Thy Face which is covered ſhall appear fair and bright, and ſhall ſhine as tranſparent Gold. Thou ſhalt anoint thy head with Oil to refreſh thee, thou ſhalt be no more in the Way-ſide for an Averſion, but for an Admiration to all; ſo that all the World ſhall ſay, it is the LORD who hath done after this manner; for it is glorious, and it hath not hitherto been ever done ſo. But ye who have revi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led the Daughter of SION, how will it go with you, when that you ſhall
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:38278:35"/>
drink of this Cup in your turn, and that your Iniquities ſhall be diſcovered? With thee, O SION, it ſhall go well, and of thy Sins there ſhall no mention be made. But with thee, O Daughter of <hi>Edom</hi> it ſhall go very bad, ſay I, the Lord of Sabaoth; for thy Sins ſhall be brought into remembrance before me.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi rend="margQuotes">
                     <hi>Iſrael's</hi> Future Faith is here re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſented as Preſent.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>O how lovely art thou my Deareſt! How doth thy Faith ſhine! How doth thy goodneſs ſparkle! How noble is thy Manner! How Friendly and Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming are thine Eyes! Come and take the reſt of my Beauty to thee: Come quickly, come, for in Friendſhip I will re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive thee, thou moſt lovely amongſt the Children of Men. And after that thou ſhalt have received from me, as much Spiritual Beauty as thou wilt, come alſo and take thy Earthly recompenſe. Ariſe! Ariſe! O Daughter of <hi>Sion,</hi> for I will come and viſit thee, I will raiſe thee up that art in the duſt: Make thy
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:38278:35"/>
ſelf ready in a moment; for I will build thee up, O thou that art thrown down: I will return again towards thee, and remain with thee until I lead thee into my Father's Houſe. I will Crown thee with Bleſſings, and make thy Face joyful. Wherefore be of good heart, for this ſhall happen to thee in a time that thou doſt not think of. And caſt thou upon me all thy Cares, for I will bear them: Lock thou up thy reſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs heart in my ſweet Love, and verily I ſay unto thee, thou ſhalt not miſs of my certain help. <hi>Amen!</hi>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p n="7">7. <hi rend="margQuotes">HE fortells a Delightful time, which ſhall preceede, and be as it were an Image of the Millennial Reign.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Be not troubled, my dear Sheep; nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther be ye ſad: Hang not down your Heads, but lift them up in my Strength, and know ye that your Deliverance is nigh; for the Hour is now come, and the time of Affliction is paſſed over; the Day of Grace appointed for all thoſe that are Called breaketh forth; for the laſt Evening-light ſhall ſhine, which
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:38278:36"/>
imperfect Splendour of the Evening ſhall out-do the Sun-beams at noon. She ſhall be Adorned in Purple, and moſt fine Gold; in the Evening of the World there ſhall breathe a mild Gale; Men upon the Earth ſhall be at Unity, (yet not all) and both great and ſmall know me, and ſhall pierce deeply into my Wiſdom. But notwithſtanding, this ſhall be put as a Type or Shadow of the Millennial Kingdom. Wherefore be glad, cleave faſt to me, live well, and above all things have Faith.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="8">8. <hi rend="margQuotes">A Prophecy that the <hi>Reubenites</hi> ſhall be deſtroy'd in their Poſterity.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Verily, Verily, I ſay unto thee, my deareſt Daughter <hi>Sion,</hi> that the Lord who hath made Heaven and Earth, is purpoſed and hath firmly reſolved, that he will gather together all the faint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hearted and baſhful, all thoſe that are oppreſſed and humbled, in ſhor, all thoſe that are upright in the ſervice of me. Unto theſe will I the Lord be Gracious, and the old <hi>Reubenites,</hi> who ſhall ſeek to deſtroy them, I will deſtroy; thoſe
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:38278:36"/>
only of them excepted, who ſhal be found of an upright heart, whom I will gather to the reſt, and they ſhall dwell together for evermore, all thoſe whom I ſhall have brought into one Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy; and they ſhall have but one Name, <hi>that is,</hi> that they are Chriſtians. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore rejoyce always in me, give thanks to my Name; be Single-hearted, be Merciful, be Upright. Fare ye well.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="9">9. <hi rend="margQuotes">How <hi>Levi</hi> alſo ſhall not eſcape.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Be thou joyful O my dear <hi>Sion,</hi> and thou <hi>Ephraim</hi> my beloved, give a great Shout; for a Gracious Viſitation ſhall now return upon thee, and the Light of my Holy Goſpel I will cauſe thee to ſee clearly: But If thou wilt not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive it, behold I have whet my Sword, and ſtretched out my Bow, and made it ready with a deadly Arrow, that I may ſtrike thee Dead in the twinckling of an Eye. For as many as receive it, I will alſo receive, and will be merciful to: but as many as are ſelf-willed and ſtiff-necked, I will ſcatter before my Face, and chaſtize with heavy Stripes,
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:38278:37"/>
both <hi>Reuben</hi> and <hi>Levi,</hi> and all that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long to them. As for thoſe who remain mine. in great mercy will I come unto them <hi>Amen!</hi>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p n="10">10. <hi rend="margQuotes">How that a Glimmering to the Kingdom of Glory is appeared, to wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to the fore-running Day-break: And how that for this reaſon, the Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gon in his Members rageth againſt the Children of Light; upon whom God will pour forth abundantly the ſtreams of his Spirit.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Be ye joyful, O my deareſt Sheep, and hearken ye to my Voice; for my Voice cryeth aloud. Hearken ye to the ſound of the Trumpet, and come ye here to me. Skip O ye Lambs upon the little Hills of God, have a good chear, be merry; for God's City ſhall be built in the days of goodneſs: Laugh, Sing aloud, Clap your hands; for my Foot is ſet upon the Bottomleſs pit, to keep the Dragon down, that he may not Spit out his deadly Poiſon, while he beholds the Dawn of the Glorious Kingdom now beginning, in which his Head ſhall be Bruiſed, and his Power
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:38278:37"/>
Shaken. But afterward through my Indulgence, he ſhall Spit forth his Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentine Poiſon amongſt my Choſen ones; yet with this difference, that they ſhall have reciv'd Power and Strength to reſiſt him. And this ſhall be a Sign to them, that they ſhall cauſe Fire to fall from Heaven, and Conſume the Ungodly; however they ſhall be wrong<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully treated and perſecuted; but ſhall not be at all concerned at it, but they will ſend out others, who muſt in like manner be treated. Notwithſtanding which there ſhall many be made mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt, who love me and keep my Word; and I will pour out upon them the Streams of the Spirit; and all things I will Praiſe-worthyly, and Gloriouſly accompliſh: And no body ſhall hinder me; for I am the LORD, and will ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fil my Word, which hath this long time been ſpoken. <hi>Amen.</hi> It ſhall come to paſs, as ſurely, as I the Lord, am the Lord. <hi>Amen.</hi>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p n="11">11. <hi rend="margQuotes">Next follows a Glorious Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe, how God's Truth ſhall break forth like Light, ſo that none ſhall be able to withſtand it, and that it ſhall fall
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:38278:38"/>
like Fire into the Eyes of the Fools, whence dread and trouble ſhall come upon them</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Should I not in this time cauſe my unfathomable Faithfulneſs, and mine E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verlaſting Love to break forth; ſeeing that the Hour is come? Yea, my Light ſhall ariſe in the Darkneſs, and my Truth ſhall Shine like the Sun in his full ſtrength; for my Statutes I will make to be acknowledged, and my Truth will I not ſuffer to lye hid in obſcurity. I will do another thing in <hi>Iſrael,</hi> yea, a ſtrange thing will I do, which ſhall drop from the Spirit of Truth, and like Fire fall into the Eyes of the Unwiſe. And if they will not receive it, Dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs ſhall ſeize upon them. O ſlumber not now ye Wiſe Virgins, but ſtand on your Watch, for the Bridegroom cometh: Go ye forth with a new noiſe, Praiſe ye, and Magnifie my Name, O ye Nations and Armies. For the <hi>New Jeruſalem</hi> is about building: Be ye then compacted every one to another in the Love, taking no thought how it ſhould be; for I am with you.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="12">
                  <pb n="31" facs="tcp:38278:38"/>12. <hi rend="margQuotes">The following one is a precious Teſtimony of Chriſt towards a Perſon of great Quality, being in the Fear of the Lord, vvhom He lifts very Graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly up.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>I the Subſtantial Truth, the Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Love, do in the Spirit bear vvit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, that I am CHRIST, the Lord of Belief, the Vanquiſher of unbelief, the Deſtroyer of doubt, the Light of Men, the Spring of Life; one that is Holy and Righteous, who deſtroyeth the Kingdom of Darkneſs, taketh avvay the Power of Hell, and pulleth out the Sting of Sin. I am JESUS CHRIST the Lord, who do reveal my ſelf, and for the Love which I bear to all Men, do witneſs in the Spirit; that tho' I do more clearly, and more Familiarly re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veal my ſelf to ſome then I do to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, as may be ſeen in <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Cephas;</hi> yet my everlaſting Love is the ſame un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to all Men; for I reſpect not the Perſon of any, but whoſoever doth well, and keepeth my Commandments the ſame is well-pleaſing unto me. Wherefore
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:38278:39"/>
I JESUS, the Lord of Life, do bear witneſs, that I am revealed after an hidden Spiritual manner in their Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits; becauſe in ſingleneſs and oneneſs I am delighted to Work: I am the very ſame Spirit that bore witneſs in the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of all the Apoſtles, namely the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Chriſt, by whoſe wounds you are healed: I am the Eternal Love, through whoſe Glory you ſtand in the Father's Preſence. Therefore Sing ye merrily, O let Heaven and the Children of God give a ſhout for joy; for my Hour is come, in which I gather in my Vintage, even them whom my Father hath given me for an everlaſting Heritage, &amp; whom I have purchaſed to my ſelf through my Croſs and Death: In which bleſſed Way, as many as are true believers, do follow me under my eaſie Yoak. I am the Way of Life, whoſoever believeth in me hath Life Everlaſting; and I will dwell in him, and he in me to Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Glory. Behold here are the Wounds, and the Marks of the Nails, for a Teſtimony in the Spirit of this my ſo burning Love! I ſpread forth my
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:38278:39"/>
Arms to take in that which is gone a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtray, to hold up that which is feeble, to ſtrengthen that which is fearful; for I will take my Flock to my Self, and feed them, for my Heart melteth to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards them. Why ſhould I not exalt my ſelf in the Sanctuary? And why ſhould I not declare my Power in the Hearts of all the Faithful? Yea, why not in all Speeches and Languages? Am not I your Shepherd? How then can I any longer ſee the Confuſion of my Flock? Give thy Voice, O Lord of Heaven, [my Father] and regard the Deſolation hereof, and behold how all things are neglected, and how my true Word which I uttered by my Prophets and my Apoſtles is looked on as nought. For what they do is all Hypocriſy, they forſake the Power of the Word, and dig themſelves out here and there their own Wells, whoſe being is in the out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Work; but the Powerful Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples of Faith [whoſe being is in the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward Ground] they deny. And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore is my Wrath kindled, and for this end am I come to Judge the Earth. But
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:38278:40"/>
who is there that hath known my mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing? And who hath been of my Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel? Nevertheleſs the Spirit, by whom ye are Sealed unto Holineſs, ſearcheth all things, even the Spirit ſo richly pou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red out on you by the Father, and by whoſe means you believe, even by his ſtrength; for it is he himſelf who vvork<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth Faith in you. Be thou then through this Spirit ſtirred up in Faith, my dear <hi>M—y</hi> Dwell thou in me, and I will dwell in thee, that thou with memaiſt live ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſtingly. Believe and ſo art thou help<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; for in believing me thou findeſt all things. Be joyful in Hope, patient in Affliction, take good heed to this I ſay, and live up to it; ſo ſhall I for ever re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>main thy faithful Friend and Brother. Wreſtle with me in the Faith, ſo ſhalt thou know me; for I will come with the Father and the Holy Ghoſt, and we will dwell with thee; for the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther loveth thee for my ſake, and the Comforter the Holy Ghoſt is with thee. In ſingleneſs and lowlineſs of Heart Sing HALLELUJAH. This is a Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony in the Spirit given from the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verlaſting
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:38278:40"/>
Chriſt Jeſus, the Conqueror of Death, Devils and Hell.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="13">13. <hi rend="margQuotes">The Grafting in again of the Olive Branches which were broken off and the breaking off of the Evil Branches, and Transplanting them into a wild place.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Peace be with you, dear Children: Speak ye now concerning the help out of <hi>Sion,</hi> and rejoice over the Salvation of <hi>Iſrael:</hi> For the hour is come, in which I bring again the Branches of the Olive, and regraft them into their Pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces; for that I am the Lord excerciſing righteouſneſs, and ſtedfaſt in keeping my Word. But as for the Evil and the Hardned, them do I again lop off, and ſend away into a wild Place. Why ſpeakeſt thou ſo loftily, O thou profli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gate one? My Juſtice I will make thee to ſee; for thou haſt nothing of thy ſelf, but all that thou haſt is from meer Grace. But be of good Comfort my <hi>Ephraim;</hi> I will provide for thee, my dear Daughter, and will deliver thee from the Scorners. I have ſaid it to
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:38278:41"/>
thee; be joyful henceforward, and fear not; for I am thy Refuge, and thy ſtrong Rock: I ſay <hi>Amen!</hi>
                  </q>
               </p>
               <p n="15">15. <hi rend="margQuotes">A very lovely Conſolation for <hi>Judah</hi> and <hi>Iſrael;</hi> with a Comfortable word to the Firſt-born of Joy in their Poſterity.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>Hope in the Lord, O <hi>Iſrael,</hi> ſhout for joy, O <hi>Judah;</hi> for the Lord hath looked upon thee in kindneſs. He ſhall make thee to rejoyce, O thou Firſt-born, in thy Poſterity: I am He that hath ſaid it; But to whom is my ſecret known, and who is there that underſtandeth my meaning? Nevertheleſs the Deep ſhall utter forth the praiſes of my Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teouſneſs, and the Clouds ſhall declare my Truth. Dear Children be not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fraid, for I am the Truth: Abide in my Truth, and what is there that can diſturb you? Unto you I am All in All. He that loveth me, hath Everlaſting Life, and is Juſtified in me, through the power of Faith. Cry aloud, lift up your Voices, for I am a wonderful God, one who levelleth the Mountains,
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:38278:41"/>
and pulleth up Men from the Deep of the Earth. Be at peace my dear <hi>Sion,</hi> Waver not my Child: Behold in thine hands I have ſigned thee: I am a God of thy Name, a Keeper of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> a Friend of <hi>Sion,</hi> a Benefactor of <hi>Ephraim.</hi> Trouble not your ſelves dear Friends, for no Evil ſhall be able to reach you; and as for what you undertake, it ſhall proſper: for I will ſet your Feet in a large place.</q>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XVIII.</head>
               <p>All theſe Teſtimonies, and many more, were given by God to this Bleſſed Maid, before I had any manner of Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quaintance with Her. Upon the Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence of which ſhe is ſo Convinced of the Divinity of this matter, that not withſtanding all the Contradiction and Oppoſition of Men, ſhe doth, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out the leaſt mixture of Doubt or Fear, believe in pure Simplicity and Child<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like Confidence, that whatever the Lord hath told, or ſhall according to the expectation of her Faith hereafter tell her, ſhall be punctually fulfil'd both in Her and in others. She knows
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:38278:42"/>
in whom ſhe Believes, and underſtands to diſtinguiſh between the Spirit of Truth, and the Spirit of Errour, with a clear Eye. She bears with thoſe who are not as yet able to own in her the Lord's Work; but withal ſhe believes that if they be of upright Hearts, they will not be ſwift to paſs Sentance upon Her; as alſo that as many as are En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lighten'd by the Divine Light, will be capable to feel that to be from God, which God has beſtow'd upon her. But in bearing thus with the weak, ſhe permits not her ſelf to be made Weak. And ſo far is ſhe from being diſturb'd at the Blaſphemous Sentence of the Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>believers, that ſhe prays for them, that God would not therefore on a ſudden bring them into Judgment, as might juſtly be fear'd, but that he would in mercy delay it; who is a God, uſing ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ribly to puniſh the Blaſphemy of im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puting that to the Devil, which pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeds from the Holy Ghoſt. She ſays, and maintains, No body can make me doubtful of that which I have ſeen and heard: No body knows the <hi>New Name,</hi>
                  <pb n="39" facs="tcp:38278:42"/>
but he that receives it: None but the Spirit of Man, which is in him, knows what is in Man; even ſo the things of God are not known to any, ſave to the Spirit of God: Now we have recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved not the Spirit of the World, but the Spirit of God, that we might be able to know what is given us of God. With this one Teſtimony of the Holy Spirit, She overthrows all the Objecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons made againſt her from Without; which for the moſt part, come from thoſe who cleave too much to the Fleſh. Notwithſtanding all which ſhe truſts, that in the end God will manifeſt His Work, ſo as all the World may own that it is even He himſelf, who hath witneſſed all theſe Words by Her.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XIX.</head>
               <p>But that you may underſtand the Method in which theſe Revelations paſs, and how this B. Maid doth not ſee with her Groſs and Corporeal Eyes, or hear with her Corporeal Ears; but doth ſee and hear the Lord in Spirit, and how ſhe doth from time to time write down from his ſweet Mouth the
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:38278:43"/>
Words which ſhe thus hears: I will here import a Teſtimony, which was given her on the Twelfth on <hi>November,</hi> in the Year MDCLXXXVIII. The LORD himſelf dictating the ſame as ſhe wrote, to the end that if any were deſirous to be inform'd concerning the manner of the Revelation, ſhe might be able to anſwer them in His own Words: Which are theſe.</p>
               <p>Peace be with you the Friends of Our JESUS, the Saints Bleſſed and Beloved. I ſpeak with you, as one Friend Speaks with another: I ſpeak at this time with the Mouth of Truth, that I may be heard; yet not outwardly by the Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dily, but inwardly by the Spiritual Ear, which is a Thouſand times more delicate then the Outward one. I ſpeak to you by my ſelf, as true God, and true Man, and cauſe my ſelf to be ſeen, not by the Eyes of the Body, but by the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ternal Eyes, the Eyes of the Spirit, of ſuch a Spirit naturally, as is united and betrothed moſt ſtrictly to me- And this manner of Sight is real, tho'
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:38278:43"/>
it be hidden and ſubtil. This I know will ſeem ſtrange to you, who do not yet underſtand my Myſteries and my Wonders: Yet I tell it you, that you may be able to diſcourſe of it properly, according to my Inſpiration. For ſo, and by this means, have I ſpoken to you all thoſe ſweet Words which you have hitherto written. I have this fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in love to ſpeak, and ſay to you: Rejoyce ye for your great Glory and Honour, ſince you are rendred ſo bright through my Righteouſneſs, as to become white as the Snow, to be cleanſed and purged from all Sin, yea to be one Heart with me, and to be my Temple and Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Habitation. Keep now the Houſe of your Heart clean, and let it be mine: neither ſuffer your corrupt ſinful Will, nor the Love of the Creatures to Lord it therein: So will I ſink down very deeply into you, and then will ariſe up again in you, and ſuch a purifying will I make within you, that you ſhall praiſe me both with Heart and Mouth. My dear little Children rejoice ye for my ſake, and be of good Courage; for I am with you. Lay your ſelves now to reſt in
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:38278:44"/>
my Holy Will, and purſue it, that I may make you the Inſtruments of my Graces and Gifts</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XX.</head>
               <p>But as the Divinity of this Affair hath been witneſſed particularly to ſome Friends, ſo hath it been to my Wife and Me. For after that God had before this, even while we were yet in <hi>Holſtein,</hi> made known to us (not by ſuch high and extraordinary Revelatiosn, but) by his Spirit in his Word, the great Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe made to <hi>Iſrael</hi> in Scripture, and the Myſtery of his Kingdom, and that we for the ſake of this, had ſuffered a great deal, it pleaſed him to let us have for about a Year ſince, the knowledge of this Gentle vvoman, of whom we had not then heard any thing, by the means of a devout Perſon, with whom we had then ſome Converſations con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Converſion of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and the Kingdom of Chriſt. For this Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon happening afterward to Travel through the Town, in which dwelt the Widow with her Daughters, was in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed by ſome Friends, how there
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:38278:44"/>
was in that Town a Godly Family, in which a young Maiden had by particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Illumination received very much from God, concerning the Future Grace and Reſtoration of the Tribes of <hi>Iſrael.</hi> As the ſaid Perſon writ this to us, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al adding, that all this Agreed with what we had been diſcourſing together; we reſolved, in the Name of God, to write to the ſaid young Gentlevvoman; from whom we received ſuch an An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer as wonderfully heartned us, and gave us preſently to ſee, that it muſt be an higher Hand that guided her's in writing.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXI.</head>
               <p>As therefore we knew not yet any thing of theſe Heavenly Teſtimonies, or of the manner in which the Lord gave and dictated them, he was pleas'd to comfort and lift us up, who were wearied, and tired, and <hi>deſpiſed before the World,</hi> for having believed, and wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſed his Kingdom by a dear Kingdom Teſtimony, which was ſent us upon <hi>October</hi> the 20th of the Year MDCXC. by this B. Maid, which here follows.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="44" facs="tcp:38278:45"/>I the Spirit of Love, I the Truth of Jeſus Chriſt, do in the Spirit witneſs and declare, that ye my dear Friends do ſtand in the Truth. In which being firmly grounded, be ſure to hold faſt the truſt of my Love, and I who am the Hope of <hi>Iſrael</hi> will bring you forth ſafe, notwithſtanding all the oppoſitions of the Incredulous; for I am a Strong Caſtle, wherein ye may ſecurely dwell. And the more ſimple ye grow, ſo much the greater delight do I take, that ye may ſee deeper and deeper into my Myſteries, which I will reveal to thoſe that are of a Contrite Heart, and will lay open to the Simple in the Faith. In this latter time I will declare my Won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders: I ſay it, who am the Lord of Faith, Jeſus Chriſt, to you my beloved, having Loved you from the beginning of your Life: It is I who bind up what is Sore, and heal what is Wounded; for I am Love, and whoſoever remains in Love dwells in God, and the Father dwells in him. Dear Friends Farewel: I have witneſſed this in the Spirit from
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:38278:45"/>
the abundance of the Love which I bear towards you: <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Reading then this Divine Exhortation &amp; Encouragement, of which we had no manner of doubt, we fell upon our Knees, giving thanks for it, and direct<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing our Vows to God the Father of our Lord Jeſus Chriſt, of Sacrificing up to him our whole Life, of placing our con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence in him preferably to all Men, and of declaring abroad his holy Truth. Hereupon we reſolved to be acquainted with ſuch dear Friends of God, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly we parted hence on the Third of <hi>November,</hi> and arrived there on the Sixth of the ſame in the Evening; where we ſaw in them much more then we could have before believed, and were immediately convinced of the Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vinity of the Matter. And for as much as they had not hitherto obſerved in the Holy Scripture that which the Lord had ſpoken to them, as God had made it knovvn to us by his Spirit; and alſo, for as much as there vvere alſo ſome things contained in thoſe Divine Teſtimonies
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:38278:46"/>
vvhich they had received, vvhich they did not as yet underſtand; and as vve confer'd one vvith another of the Gift vvhich vve had received from God, vve vvere mightily comforted together: We, my Wife and I, for that we ſaw how that which we had Comprehended and found out in the Prophets and in the <hi>Apocalypſe,</hi> concerning future things, vvas not according to our ovvn Fancy, but in the Truth according to the Senſe of God: And they, for that by our In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructions they came to knovv, hovv that vvhat the Lord had given them after an Extraordinary manner, had been before conceived by the Spirit of God, in the Writings of the Prophets and Apoſtles.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXII.</head>
               <p>We vvere then alſo mightily refreſh'd by our dear Lord and Saviour, vvho during this Intervievv, vvas Graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly pleaſed to give us this follovving Teſtimony.</p>
               <p>Be ye joyful, be ye joyful, ye vvho knovv my Name, and have my Love;
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:38278:46"/>
for I will do great things for you: Therefore be ye chearful. Look, and obſerve well, for I am here: I go in to the Work. Be ye affectionate, be filled with Joy, and with Pſalms of Praiſe. Verily I ſay unto you, the Hour cometh, and is now come, in which I judge according to Truth and Righteouſneſs: I am Chriſt the Lord, who have Compaſſion over dear <hi>Sion,</hi> and over <hi>Ephraim</hi> my Beloved. I have brought you together with a Bleſſing, and am in the midſt of you: I am the Light, and the Love, and I delight to abide with you. I have ſaid it unto you, but who is there that can diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver that which is my Intention? <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men!</hi> I have ſaid it unto you.</p>
               <p>Now according as the Lord, who both knows all things, and can make all things ſubſervient to his Will, had ſaid it, ſo it came to paſs: While by his Marvellous and holy Conduct we have now had with us this dear Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly for theſe Nine Months paſt, which we had not at our firſt Meeting any reaſon to hope for, and have accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:38278:47"/>
to his Will been by wonderful ſteps brought to dwell together. So upon the Tenth day of <hi>November</hi> we parted thence with Joy, and were led home in Peace. But as ſoon we were return'd, the Slanders began afreſh to be reviv'd againſt us; but we took new ſtrength from all the Benefits which we had received from the Lord, and one day we had this Encouragement given us.</p>
               <p>Peace be with you, ye Bleſſed, here am I, your loving Saviour, your dear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Friend and Brother, whoſe Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Love and Faithfulneſs cannot be bounded, for my Love is flaming, and my Heart is all on fire: But ye do not yet conceive my Love, it is ſo ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry great. O be glad, O cry aloud and ſing, O praiſe ye, and magnifie my Name, for my Right ſhall get the Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory, and my Truth ſhall be made great: It ſhall ariſe, and ſpread like the break of the Morning. Rejoice ye in my help, ye who are driven out: I run after you, to bring you back, to lead you home unto me: I who ſpeak
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:38278:47"/>
it am Chriſt the Lord. Believe only, and hold faſt to me, and then let not your Hearts be troubled; for I will make my Name to be great, and my Statutes I will cauſe to be received. Ye are thoſe whom I love, confeſs ye therefore that I am the Lord from E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verlaſting, who lye not, that I ſhould be ſlack to fulfil the Word of my Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe: And I would that every one ſhould be converted and live. My Hand is not ſhortened, my Faithful Mercy hath no end, and my Love grows not cold. O Sing with a joyful Melody, for my Hour is come, and the Day of the Bridegroom is at hand. Love ye one another, and live happily. To your upright Friends in the Truth, make my Love to be known, for as much as I have heard them, and my Heart loveth them for evermore. <hi>A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>But as Slanders encreaſed more and more, we were again ſtirr'd up, and encourag'd in this manner.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="50" facs="tcp:38278:48"/>Peace be with you: Fear not, for my Mercy ſhall never be removed from you, neither my Love ſhall at all ceaſe; for it ſurpaſſeth every breadth, and every heighth, ſo exceeding great is it; wherefore it's fit that it ſhould make it ſelf ſeen and heard in all Corners, and in all Places, for it is therefore riſen very richly upon you, and advanceth forward in Might. And I ſay once more, that when I ſhall come, and do a new thing, and deliver the Priſoners of <hi>Sion,</hi> then this Love ſhall ſhine forth, and be revealed with power. Be not then afraid, O my <hi>Zion;</hi> nor be thou caſt down, O my <hi>Ephraim;</hi> for thy Towers ſhall be built up, and I will beget my ſelf in thee. Be joyful therefore; ſince all my Prophetical Words I maintain, and do according to my Everlaſting Purpoſe. For this cauſe ſhout for Joy, O Daughter of <hi>Sion:</hi> And play thou <hi>Ephraim</hi> in the Cymbals and Dances: Shout for Joy ye Heavens, the Work of my Hands, and let all the Sons of God give a luſty ſhout, yea all thoſe that call upon my
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:38278:48"/>
Name, and all thoſe that are faint and caſt down, let them be joyful for the Glorious Day of my Appearance, in which I will, together with all the Faithful, both thoſe who live, and thoſe who are faln aſleep, Reign Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>umphantly over my Enemies. This is what I wait for now; be ye therefore joyful for my coming: For Lo! I come, and rule with Might in that Kingdom, and no Body dare reſiſt me, for it is the Day of my Marriage, wherein I will drink with you of the new Fruit of the Kingdom: Wherefore rejoice ye, and ſing aloud; for this is my Word of Truth.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXIII.</head>
               <p n="1">1. Our mutual Love encreaſed, and we became one Heart, and one Soul. With this Brotherly Love theſe Friends were ſtirred up to come and ſpeak with us; yet they could not do it, without they were certain it was God's Will: Which having waited to know, they receiv'd, according to their deſire, this gracious Anſwer.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="52" facs="tcp:38278:49"/>Make your ſelves ready to go along in Simplicity and Silence to my Faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Servants, whom I love. I will be with you, and my Love ſhall guide you. Be ye therefore of one Mind in the Spirit, and go thither in Charity; for as much as ye now know my holy Will. Live contentedly, and fear not; for I fight for you, and my Truth is your Defence and Buckler.</p>
               <p n="2">2. This brought us Joy and Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing: Our Houſe too like that hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore of <hi>Obed-Edom</hi> was bleſt; in ſuch wiſe, that being far from wanting any thing, we were from their Preſence la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den, as it were, with Divine Bleſſings ſucceeding one another, and eſpecially with many gracious Teſtimonies, by which the LORD animated us after this manner.</p>
               <p>I the God of <hi>Abraham, Iſaac,</hi> and <hi>Jacob,</hi> declare to thee the Truth, and Hope, in which the Fathers have ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped: Yea, yea, I witneſs it, even I the true and faithful Witneſs, the Firſt-born from the Dead, that thou maiſt
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:38278:49"/>
bear witneſs of the Truth of my King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom; for it is a true Kingdom, a Kingdom nigh at hand to you. Yea, yea, it is certain: I come ſuddenly. Turn ye neither to the right, nor to the left, all ye who know my Truth; and rejoice in the Faith. I embrace you all with my Love, and I ſay, Be ye happy, and praiſe my Name.</p>
               <p n="3">3. And ſoon afterward we receiv'd alſo this Holy Revelation from the Riches of his Goodneſs.</p>
               <p>Dear Friends whom I have brought together, and whom I have ſanctified to my ſelf, Peace be with you. My Countenance is over you, and the Light of it ſhines upon you in much Love: Ariſe therefore, lift up your Voice to me in my Praiſe: Be not terrified, for I am in the midſt of you, and lead you according to my Hearts deſire. Be ye of one Mind, and hold faſt one to another; for I am with you, and bleſs you for ever. I greet you all with my Love, and preſs you to my Breaſt, and declare to you that
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:38278:50"/>
the Light is riſen, and the Dawn of the Glorious Bridal Day begins to ſpread. The Bride rejoices for the Nuptial Day, the Turtle Dove lets her ſelf be heard, the Day breaks forth, the Morning Star gets up, the Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of the Father make merry toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and my Bride is full of Joy, and to her a Golden Shield is given, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fend her againſt the Darkneſs, which alſo breaks forth in its Fog. The Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gon Arms himſelf with thoſe who be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>long to him, why ſhould I not then Arm my Bride, and let her ſee what ſhe is to enjoy? The Day-break muſt go before, and Antichriſt muſt behold, how the Light riſes up againſt his Darkneſs. Cry therefore aloud for Joy, ye bleſſed, for you ſhall be glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly Armed againſt the Wicked; for I am your King, who Conquer the Kingdom. I come ſuddenly: <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXIV.</head>
               <p n="1">1. My Wife in the Humility of her Heart, and in Faith beſought the Lord, by the Elect Maid, that he would re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veal in what Church we are at pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent;
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:38278:50"/>
ſince according to His own Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication, the Seven Churches in the <hi>Revelation,</hi> do ſet forth Seven ſucceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſive Periodical Communities. To which Prayer the Lord was pleaſed to Anſwer thus.</p>
               <p>Peace be with thee— How ſhould I be diſpleaſed with thee, that thou ſpeakeſt before me? For I am very Charitable toward thee. Hear then my Word, thou little Dove: Lo! the Church of <hi>Laodicea</hi> fighteth powerfully againſt the Beaſt; and that of <hi>Phila<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>delphia,</hi> in which you are at preſent, ends gloriouſly with Spirit and Power in the Believers. And this Church ſhall compleat, that which I have cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen; and to it ſhall be the Gathering together of the Peoples that Believe. This I witneſs, that thou maiſt in like manner witneſs, that it is true. Fare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wel—</p>
               <p n="2">2. Upon the Thirtieth of <hi>March,</hi> MDCXCI. there came this following dear Teſtimony.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="56" facs="tcp:38278:51"/>Peace, Happineſs, and Salvation be with you, O ye Elect, whom I have taken up into my Eternal Communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, whom I my ſelf have for my plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure hallowed in my Eyes. Give ear then ye beloved and bleſſed of me. The Bride is for my pleaſure Everlaſtingly hallowed, and is in each one ſingly by me purified, and preſerved. Happy are ye, who live in this preſent day! All that have been Rebellious muſt re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn to their Duty, and all that have gone aſtray will I bring home again with Joy. But as for the Virgins they are pure, they are cleanſed, and ſet a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part, they are Redeemed to be my Firſt-fruits, that ſo they may be the firſt to open the Matrix; therefore are they neareſt to me, for they are Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deemed from among Men, they are the Sap and the Balm, which gets vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gorouſly above the Old, and breaks the <hi>Matrix</hi> in the New-birth. And theſe being made Perfect, who among the Daughters ſhall be liken'd unto them? She, the Virgin Bride, ſhall be a Lio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and from this moment ſhe ſhall
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:38278:51"/>
be dear to her Father. <hi>Jacob</hi> is dear to him that begat him, and <hi>Benjamin</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the reſt beloved by his Father. A Thouſand are the moſt Beloved, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hey that are choſen out before the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eſt in the Love, are a Thouſand which cannot be numbred. Be ye but more ſimple, O my beloved; ſo ſhall ye un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtand me, and learn my Wiſdom. Live but well, I am with my Love in the midſt of you, and by my Truth I knit you faſt together. Peace be with you.</p>
               <p n="3">3. Concerning this matter, it pleaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed him in kindneſs to let us underſtand more by ſpeaking to us afterward by the ſame Inſtrument in this wiſe.</p>
               <p>Peace be with you all that are ſet a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part, whom I love: Happineſs, Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, and Might be with you. Bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed are ye who believe, and who keep me in the Purity of Truth. Come now my little Lambs, leap ye upon Mount <hi>Sion:</hi> Come ye Servants of God, ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther your ſelves together under my Wings; and let every one that will
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:38278:52"/>
take ſtrength from me, to overcome the Beaſt and his Mark. Look ye in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardly into my Truth, and obſerve it; for I will do many Signs, to the end that Men may underſtand that I am the LORD. The Hundred Forty and Four Thouſand is a great Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, and they are from the beginning Redeemed from among Men, that they might be the Firſt that are Hallowed unto the Lord; who are accordingly from the beginning made Holy to Me, and for a Teſtimony are they offered up unto Me. Great is the Myſtery! Mark it well. Theſe are Virgins, for they have received the Name of my Virginity, and ſing the Song which no Body is able to learn but themſelves: They come therefore to me upon Mount <hi>Sion,</hi> and are there Sealed for a Witneſs over all the Sects, before that they can come along with me to the Judgment. But who is able to know in what manner they ſhall come? They are found True in theſe laſt Times; lo, they come in the very laſt time: Herewith obſerve well the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſtation
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:38278:52"/>
of the Two Witneſſes, and behold how I order all things wiſely. I have been, and now I come again in Glory, to rule over mine Enemies; that I may root them out, and deſtroy their Memory. Lo! when I come, and move the Earth, then ſhall the Myſtery break forth. Be watchful, lift up your Heads, for ye know not yet what ye ſhall be, till that I come to the Glory. And then when I ſhall deſcend in this Glory with all the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lect, ye ſhall all ſing a New Song. Live well ye Bleſſed Ones; I will give you my Spirit, who ſhall make the Myſtery clear to you, according as I do mean it.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXV.</head>
               <p n="1">1. Concerning the Firſt Reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, which is to be in the Time of the Two Great Witneſſes, ſhortly after the expiring of the Twelve Hundred and Threeſcore Days. Which Reſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rection the Lord aſſures us in this fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowing Teſtimony to be Corporeal and Real, and not only Spiritual and Figu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rative, as ſome do imagine.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="60" facs="tcp:38278:53"/>Dear Friend, I thy Faithful Savi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>our greet thee. Thou underſtandeſt my Truth, how that the Righteous are to ſtand with me in the Judgment, and that both in Body and Soul. They come likewiſe with the Two Witneſſes, as an Army that is well ordered, and that is adorned with my Strength. Then ſhall they Execute Juſtice in my Might, and through it poſſeſs the Kingdom. For they are the Children of the Firſt Reſurrection, and they ſhall lift up my Name, and my Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments.</p>
               <p n="2">2. Again the Lord ſaid,</p>
               <p>The Dead ſhall Riſe again in like manner as I am Riſen, and ſhall Reign with me in Paradiſe: But the <hi>Jews</hi> ſhall receive their Promiſe here upon the Earth, according to my Everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Truth; I having prepared it for them, and given it unto them.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXVI.</head>
               <p n="1">1. Some time after this, we having now receiv'd ſuch abundant Convicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the Loving-kindneſs and Graci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:38278:53"/>
of the Lord, it was deem'd not unfit to propoſe to Him in the Faith this Queſtion, <hi>viz.</hi> How that paſſage, <hi>Luke</hi> 21.25. <hi>And there ſhall be Signs in the Sun, and in the Moon, and in the Stars,</hi> ought to be underſtood, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Litterally or Myſtically? The Anſwer was what follows.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Amen,</hi> I ſay unto thee, there ſhall be many Signs in the Heavens: For Nature ſhall be moved, and ſhall be driven into a diſorderly heap; till that in the end there ſhall be obtained a Reſt, through the means of my Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mighty Word, even in Nature it ſelf. And thus thoſe who would appear as the bright Stars in their own Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, ſhall with Nature be ſhaken; for as much as they are under Nature. And theſe ſhall in great diſorder drive one another into Wrath, Cruelty, Murder, and ſuch like: And ſo ſhall they tumble down, and be darkened. And then ſhall the Peace-makers, and the Meek, the Child-like, and the Simple be ſatisfied, and ſhall enter in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Glory.</p>
               <p n="2">
                  <pb n="62" facs="tcp:38278:54"/>2. Upon the ſame Day, which was the Seventh of <hi>May,</hi> the Lord was alſo pleas'd to Reveal, how by the <hi>Beaſt</hi> was to be underſtood Antichriſt, by the <hi>Whore</hi> the Popedom, and by the <hi>Two-horned Beaſt</hi> the <hi>Romiſh</hi> Clergy, and thoſe that are like to them: And that the great City, or Myſtical <hi>Baby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lon,</hi> is <hi>Rome,</hi> as alſo ſome Myſteries concerning the Tribe of <hi>DAN.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Dear <hi>J—n,</hi> I the Everlaſting Truth, the Beginner and Finiſher of the Kingdom, Jeſus Chriſt, do ſay un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to thee, that thou haſt rightly compre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hended the Whore, the Beaſt, and the great City; for it is I that have made thee to comprehend them: And many ſhall comprehend this matter, and ſhall find out yet herein more Wiſdom, for I am the Truth, and I will reveal the ſame even unto Infants. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore be not afraid ye bleſſed, for the time cometh when it ſhall be declared openly, and ſhall be preached in the Houſe-tops. Yea, <hi>Amen,</hi> I have ſaid it: Even the Lord, the Lord.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="63" facs="tcp:38278:54"/>Now concerning <hi>DAN,</hi> he is a wicked Serpent, a corrupt Generation, that leadeth only unto Darkneſs, for all wickedneſs ſhall meet together in him, and from him ſhall the Man of Sin be revealed. Therefore not any out of him are Sealed, for they are Vipers; and none of the Firſt-born are found amongſt them; but they are all har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dened and abominable; out of many Nations, Languages and Tongues. My Spirit ſhall now lead you into all Truth, and guide you ſtill as little Children in Simplicity, and I will ſurround you with my Brightneſs, in ſuch a manner as you may ſee into my very Heart, how it danceth for Joy. As for thoſe of the Tribe of <hi>Dan,</hi> who do ſtand in the Judaiſm, they ſhall alſo be Converted, but not all of them. For as many as belong to the Beaſt, will preſently turn back to him, and will receive his Mark.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXVII.</head>
               <p n="1">1. In this manner our Gracious God, and Father in Chriſt, hath frequently viſited us with Teſtimonies of this
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:38278:55"/>
kind: And then eſpecially when I was un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der great Apprehenſions from the Threat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings of Enemies, by reaſon of a Book that was Publiſhed, concerning <hi>the Kingdom of Chriſt,</hi> I was richly Comforted with theſe words.</p>
               <p>Look here, my Brother, it is I who do it; that I may accompliſh it; even ſo as I have purpoſed to do it. And if I be thy Tower and thy Fortreſs, who is he that can offend thee? For this reaſon ſet up now thy Standard in my Name, for I will de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy them, when I awake up, but I will be with thee, and with thee will I fight a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Enemies; yea, yea, it is I who do it, therefore be thou joyful in my ſtrength, and let nothing hinder thee from doing it, for I am the Lord thy God who accompliſh this thing my ſelf. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">2. As the Calumnies yet more and more encreaſed againſt me, I received ſtill fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Comfort, of which this word of Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony that follows is an Inſtance.</p>
               <p>Be not wearied in patience thou bleſſed One, even as I am not wearied. How<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, as for the Implacable, them I will caſt out into Darkneſs: But have thou a good Courage, and be not faint in the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion of my Truth, for one Day thou ſhalt be Victorious, and having obtained a glori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:38278:55" rendition="simple:additions"/>
Conqueſt, ſhalt then Feed upon the Fruits of thy Labour. Therefore be thou refreſhed in my ſtrength, which ſhall be given to thee in abundance.</p>
               <p n="3">3. In the ſame Month I received of the Lord another powerful witneſs, proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from the freeneſs of his Grace, which pierced me into the Soul and Spirit, yea, into the Marrow and Bones; as may eaſily be imagined by any one, who ſhall but-weigh the Circumſtances which accompani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the ſame; my Wife, and I, in Company with the Bleſſed Maid, and with her Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther and Siſters, whom we could not leave alone in the Houſe, took a Journey to <hi>Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beck,</hi> to ſet in order all my Affairs, in which by the Deceaſe of my Father from hence, by reaſon of my holy Function: I left my Wife and theſe good Friends at <hi>Lubeck,</hi> and returned Hither by Poſt. I arrived here upon <hi>Sunday,</hi> and the very ſame Evening at Six a Clock, I was filled with ſuch a Divine Joy that came upon me, as an Armed Man; as in all my Life I had never felt the like, though my dear Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly Father, by the ſweet Call of his Mouth, has oftentimes put into me Life and Gladneſs: In this Joy I had a Fore-taſte of the Glory of the World to come, and ſaw in a Moment that which God hath
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:38278:56"/>
prepared for thoſe that Love him; by the means whereof my Heart was ſo Enlarged, that I thought my ſelf ſtrong enough to throw down Walls and Pillars, but there happening to be ſome Strangers then at the Table, I concealed this Joy, as much as ever I could, till that it was impoſſible to hide it longer, and then I began with a Voice of Jubilee to Sing.</p>
               <q>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Sion</hi> heard the Watchmen Sing,</l>
                  <l>Her Heart inflam'd with Joy does ſpring,</l>
                  <l>She wakes, ſhe riſes ſtrait, and haſtes away:</l>
                  <l>Her Friend comes down in Glory Bright,</l>
                  <l>Rich, full of Grace, of Truth, and Might:</l>
                  <l>Her Morning dawns, her Star proclaims the Day.</l>
                  <l>Come now Celeſtial Crown.</l>
                  <l>Dear <hi>Jeſu,</hi> God's Eternal Son.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Hoſanna.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Into the Joyful Court we follow all,</l>
                  <l>And Celebrate with Dance and Feſtival,</l>
                  <l>The Happy Nuptial Day.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Hallelujah.</hi>
                  </l>
               </q>
               <p>[The ſame a little Paraphras'd.]</p>
               <q>
                  <l>Hark, hark, from <hi>Salem</hi>'s Tow'rs the Watchmen ſing!</l>
                  <l>The ſignal of the long-expected King.</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Sion</hi>'s Courts with loud <hi>Hoſanna</hi>'s ring.</l>
                  <l>
                     <pb n="67" facs="tcp:38278:56"/>See how with eager Joy all Hearts around</l>
                  <l>Tremble, and dance to the Melodious Sound.</l>
                  <l>She ſhakes her from the Duſt, ſhe flies all Gay</l>
                  <l>To meet, or to prevent the Glorious Day.</l>
                  <l>In ſolemn Pomp her Joy from Heav'n deſcends,</l>
                  <l>Him mighty Truth, and ev'ry Grace attends.</l>
                  <l>She ſees her beauteous Morning-ſtar ariſe,</l>
                  <l>And bright <hi>Aurora</hi> Purpling round the Skies.</l>
                  <l>Now come Dear Glorious Crown, Lord <hi>Jeſu</hi> come;</l>
                  <l>And lead us to our long loſt, wiſht for, Home.</l>
                  <l>We into the Inmoſt Court all follow Thee,</l>
                  <l>The Glorious, Happy, ſtill Eternity.</l>
               </q>
               <p>[Or thus, according to the Letter.]</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Sion</hi> heard the Watchmen ſing; Her Heart ſpringeth for Joy. She awaketh, and riſeth up preſently: Her Joy cometh down from Heaven Gloriouſly: In Grace ſtrong, in Truth mighty: Her Light breaketh out, her Star is riſen. Now come dear Crown, Lord <hi>Jeſu</hi> the Son of God. <hi>Hoſannah.</hi> We all follow into the Joyful Court, and keep the Supper.</p>
               <p n="4">4. My whole Family obſerv'd this Joy in me with Aſtoniſhment, and my Son's Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor ſaid, There muſt certainly ſome Great Thing have paſſed at <hi>Lubeck</hi> at this very time, and that we were now in the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:38278:57"/>
of <hi>Their</hi> Joy. This Adventure, the next Day I ſent by the Ordinary Poſt to my Dear Wife, and the very ſame Day, being <hi>Monday,</hi> ſhe writ alſo to me, by a good Friend, what had paſſed with them at <hi>Lubeck,</hi> in that very ſame Hour, when I was ſeiz'd with ſo extraordinary a Joy. Which Letter I broke open in the preſence of Two Pious Young Ladies, who were come thither from <hi>Staden,</hi> on purpoſe to Viſit this Dear B. Maid. And having but a Minute before related to them, that which had happen'd to me upon the <hi>Sunday</hi> Even<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, I read to them theſe words of the ſaid Letter.</p>
               <p>
                  <q>Child, prithee write to me, how thou didſt find Thy ſelf upon <hi>Sunday</hi> at Six a Clock in the Afternoon, and whether thou didſt not then feel in thy Heart a certain Joy: For about that time the Lord ſpake to Thee with ſo much Af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fection, and ſo ſtirr'd thee up, as is not by me expreſſible. Of which thou maiſt beſt judge from the Teſtimony that is here ſent thee.</q>
               </p>
               <p n="5">5. Which I afterward read, and is as fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows.</p>
               <p>Courage! my Elect one: Make haſte, and meet me; for I am riſen up to come toward thee, yea, toward thee; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore come I ſo lovingly, that I may knit
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:38278:57"/>
my ſelf unto thee. For mine Heart is wounded, therefore am I ſo enflamed, and therefore am I ſo very Zealous for thy ſake. Receive then my Living Breath, and Burn thou ſo, that the Fire of it may give a loud and crackling noiſe: And let thy Zeal be ſuch, that the Flame of it may break vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lently forth. For I come leaping upon thee on a ſudden, and I throw down the Mountains with the Voice of my Coming. Yea, yea: <hi>Amen! Amen!</hi> I am JEHOVAH the Lord.</p>
               <p n="6">6. Having read this, I was mightily ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priz'd, and letting the Two Young Ladies read it themſelves, they were much Aſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd at it, and Magnify'd God, who deals thus wonderfully with his Children. As this now for my own part gave me perfect Satisfaction, that my dear Saviour was reſolv'd, by thus raiſing my Heart, in the very ſame Hour wherein he gave me this Animating Word, at the diſtance of Ten <hi>[German]</hi> Miles from hence, to Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vince me (as it accordingly did) of the Truth of this Divine Teſtimony, in ſuch a manner, as I might not hereafter have room for any Doubt of His Words, which ſhould be ſent to me at any other time: So on the other ſide, my Wife, with the reſt of our Friends at <hi>Lubeck,</hi> were in like manner
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:38278:58"/>
hereby ſtrengthen'd, and by it fully aſſur'd, even to that Degree as it is not poſſible to be more, that it was the LORD himſelf, and no other, who could ſpeak ſo by this Bleſſed Lady; as He that is only Powerful to reveal his Wonders in the Hearts of Men, to His own Praiſe.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXVIII.</head>
               <p>Neither muſt we paſs over what the Lord with great Faithfulneſs, and Love An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer'd to a certain Godly Doctor, but who was of the Reform'd Religion, and a migh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty Defender of <hi>Particulariſm;</hi> who having hop'd to Convince others of that Opinion, was himſelf well ſatisfied to find the Truth, touching Particular Grace and Predeſtina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. This then is the Anſwer that he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd from the Lord.</p>
               <p>Peace be with thee: Hear now my Word, with a ſimple, child-like Heart. Behold! I the Lord, even the Lord JEHOVAH, who upon the Cherubim and Seraphim am ſeated, who am from Everlaſting, and who bring you forth in my Everlaſting Love: How ſhould I, whoſe Compaſſion is Everlaſting and Unconfined, make a Cul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling out of ſome before others? Far be this from my Great and Univerſal Mercy. Lo, when my Heart was moved, and my Bow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>els yearned within me, then broke forth the Fire of Love, and paſſed in the ſame
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:38278:58"/>
inſtant over All Men, that were fallen in <hi>Adam:</hi> And there was no Preference of A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny; for I bear them All in my Womb, e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven in my Mercy, as if they were but One, yea, as if they were but One cold and life<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs Burden. Then did my Love break forth, and I became Fleſh, and gave my ſelf for them, and quickned them all with my Blood throughout, and looſened them from the cold Darkneſs: For they were before me but as One, and I choſe not Any, but ſuffered my Love to go forth over All. Whoſoever then cleaveth not to me, turn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth to the Darkneſs, and his Deſtruction is not from me; I am not guilty of it. Who can ſound out the Extent of my Love, and of my Mercy? Which is infinitely greater than you either know or underſtand. Wherefore forget that which is behind, namely, all impertinent Curioſity; for my Faithfulneſs and my Love ſurpaſs all Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding. And follow thou me as a little Child, and ſo ſhalt thou live: For he that feareth me, and doth that which is righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teous, is well-pleaſing in my ſight. Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold thou little Worm of <hi>Jacob,</hi> I JESUS CHRIST, the Faithful, and the True, do anſwer thee in all Mildneſs and Love; for I am the Love. Behold, what is it that ſhould cauſe me to do more for the Salva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of one, than for that of another?
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:38278:59"/>
Far be it from my Faithfulneſs to do ſo. For as to <hi>Adam</hi> the Law was given, that he ſhould not eat of the Fruit of the Tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil, but at the ſame time the will of doing it was not ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken from him, ſo that if he had remained in Simplicity, and not followed his Appe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tite in eating of this Tree, he ſhould have continued before me in Innocence; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as through diſobedience eating againſt the Commandment, he fell into Darkneſs: In like manner all Mankind, that are fallen in him, are under the ſame Circumſtances: They have Light and Darkneſs ſet before them, and beſides this they have my Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, the Spirit of Truth, that unperceiva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly, and after an hidden manner, inviteth them, and driveth them; for I will not the Death of a Sinner, but that every one be Converted and Live. It doth not yet openly appear, how I am gracious to Call, and to lead with power the whole World out of the Fall; in as much as my Love is over all every where, and is alike to all Men. Whoſoever therefore will not be Converted to the Light, but letteth him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf be ſurprized by the Serpent, the ſame is ſeparated from me, and I watch over that Perſon for Judgment: And if ſo it happen that there remain in ſuch ſome good thing of mine, that ſhall be for a Witneſs
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:38278:59"/>
againſt him. Be thou well aſſured, that into a Soul which is ſo impure I do not en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter: For after that I have cauſed my Grace to take care of him, and he receiveth me not, neither heareth my Call unto his Soul, to return from his Fallen Eſtate, I ſay un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to ſuch, let him that is Wicked be Wicked ſtill; as unto him that is Righteous, let him be Righteous ſtill. Thus it is in very truth: As for thy ſelf be thou doing good, and walking in Simplicity, as becometh a well-inſtructed Child: For many Errours, and many Diviſions ſhall yet ſpring forth from theſe haughty Spirits of Reaſon; but the Children of the Simple ſhall be preſerv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and then ſhall the Myſtery be unvailed, and they ſhall be One in Me.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXIX.</head>
               <p n="1">1. Now notwithſtanding that we had ſo many Great Things before us, which God was pleas'd to beſtow upon us, in much abundance from the Fountain of his Love and Mercy, we did not communicate them to any one, unleſs it were to ſome in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timate Friends, in whoſe Secreſie we could confide: As being very far from ſeeking by this means to gain our ſelves a Name. And the B. Maid her ſelf, with her Family, kept this Miracle of God conceal'd for the ſpace of Twelve Years: Neither had it to this very day been ever made Publick, had not
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:38278:60"/>
the bringing it forth been affected by o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, and in a wonderful manner. For Perſons began to be inquiſitive about what ſhould be the meaning of the Viſits, which we received from ſo many Perſons of Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity: And there ran a Report up and down, that there was in my Houſe a Maid that had the Falling-ſickneſs, and could Vaniſh. The Original of which Report was probably this, That this Elect Maid had upon <hi>Whitmonday</hi> receiv'd ſo great an Elevation of the Spirit, that for more than half an Hour, we beholding her Face all the while as the Face of an Angel, ſhe continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally prais'd the LORD, and directed us to him, as to him that was only worthy to receive Praiſe and Honour. Then we were in Doubt, Whether we ought to hide all that God had done to us? Or whether we ought, if it were demanded of us, plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and roundly to averr the Truth? Which difficulty preſs'd us the more, in that it ſo happen'd, that about this time my Brethren of the Clergy, were afreſh ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treamly buſied in the Controverſie of Chriſt's Reign. As we were therefore conſidering what was beſt for us to do in this Caſe, we receiv'd upon the Ninth of <hi>Auguſt</hi> this Anſwer from the Lord.</p>
               <p>Peace be with you, O ye that are trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled: I have turned my Face to you, that
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:38278:60"/>
I may be gracious unto you. Be not then afraid, for my Thoughts to you-ward are peaceable. If you be quiet, and wait in patience, you will come to ſee into my Wiſdom. Verily I ſay unto you, a great Mercy is ſhewn you: And when the Hour ſhall come, it ſhall be made all manifeſt, that you may behold how wiſely I have acted. Yea, nothing that I have ſpoken to you, ſhall be in vain: Lo, I have ſaid no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing to you in vain: Believe this. For it muſt be, that every thing yet come to paſs, and be accompliſhed according to my holy Deſign. O thou Baſhful one, that with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>draweſt thy ſelf, be not aſham'd: For I my ſelf will do good unto thee, and thou ſhalt be greatly honoured in my preſence. As I live, it muſt needs be, that all that is Paradiſiacal be again reſtored, and all that I have ſpoken be fulfilled. Who is there that knoweth the Glory of my Bride, then when I ſhall effectually Eſpouſe her, or ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, when the Eſpouſals ſhall be publiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed? And in like manner as I was mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſted in the Fleſh to Die for you, ſo muſt the Bleſſed<note n="*" place="margin">This was the Name of the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of this Elect Maid, who deceaſed the Fourth of <hi>Auguſt</hi> this very Year 1691. with theſe Words in her Mouth, <hi>Death is become a Jeſt.</hi>
                  </note> 
                  <hi>Gerdrude</hi> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>receive her Promiſe,
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:38278:61"/>
when that which is Paradiſiacal ſhall come, when the Lambs ſhall leap on Mount <hi>Leba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>non,</hi> and ſhall wait upon the Marriage. Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily I ſay unto you, all things muſt be ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>filled through the Seventh Number: And that which I ſay to you at this time, you underſtand not, but the Hour cometh in which ye ſhall underſtand it. Be joyful and couragious; for I am the LORD, and I will not ſuffer you to periſh. When therefore the Hour ſhall come that it ſhall be required of you, confeſs and deny not, for I my ſelf will have it to be declared. Be ye then at reſt, looking up to my Goodneſs.</p>
               <p n="2">2. Now, behold! juſt at this very in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant, there comes hither a certain Cler<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gy man, who ſpreads it abroad among di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe Perſons, that a Propheteſs was here. The Rumour of which coming to the Ears of the Senate, they ſent their Secretary to me, to take my Examinations upon this Head. I anſwer'd, That though I did not pretend to make her paſs for a Propheteſs, ſhe had receiv'd from God great and extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary Gifts, which I would make no difficulty to diſcover to them, if it were deſir'd; requeſting in the mean time the favour, that they would let me know the Perſon who had advis'd them of theſe
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:38278:61"/>
things. Hereupon the matter was vari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly diſcours'd; and the Calumnies being very many, one of which was, that ſhe had a Spirit of Divination in her; it pleas'd the moſt Righteous God upon the Eleventh of the ſame Month, to vindicate her in theſe Words.</p>
               <p>Shout for joy, O ye Nations: And be ye joyful, O ye Heavens. For to vindicate I am riſen up, yea, to vindicate my Daugh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter <hi>Sion.</hi> I will deſtroy the Blood of the Dragon from the Face of the Earth; for my Wrath is kindled, and who is there that can withhold me? The Foundations upon which he ſtandeth ſhall be ſhaken, when I awake up: As for his Boils and his Wounds, behold they ſhall find no Cure; there ſhall not be any hope left of healing them. Wherefore I ſay, as I live I will utterly deſtroy him, and will caſt out his Skull to be devoured by the Dogs. Have Courage then, O Daughter of <hi>Sion,</hi> in all Afflictions; for thou ſhalt ſuffer for my Name ſake, and ſhalt be rejected and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpiſed: But rejoice thou, and be of good Heart, for the Light ſhall be divided from the Darkneſs, and I the LORD will be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come to thee a ſure Habitation, and a ſtrong Rock. Yea: <hi>Amen!</hi> My Wonders muſt be revealed, and it muſt be done ſo. Wherefore lift up your Heads, and be
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:38278:62"/>
without fear; for I am in the midſt of you: Yea: <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXX.</head>
               <p>As upon the Sixteenth of <hi>Auguſt,</hi> it fell out that One in Preaching out of the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Chapter of the Prophet <hi>Joel,</hi> did not clear him up according to the Senſe and Meaning of the Holy Ghoſt, but maintain'd, that God would give no more ſuch extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary Revelations to Mankind; one of our Friends that was then preſent, being much troubled at this Explication, was de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſirous that the Lord our Saviour, who had hitherto witneſs'd ſo much favour and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deſcenſion towards us, would be pleas'd himſelf to declare the true Intent of that paſſage, and to give us his Divine Inſtructi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on upon it. And accordingly the next day, He vouchſaf'd to open the Prophet's Meaning, and at the ſame time to let us ſee his Wrath againſt thoſe, who give ſuch Prevaricating Explications to his Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſies.</p>
               <p>I the GOD of <hi>Abraham, Iſaac,</hi> and <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cob;</hi> the God of <hi>Sion;</hi> will bring out of Mount <hi>Sion</hi> Deliverance to my <hi>Ephraim,</hi> who is the Child of my Love. Verily, as I live, the Fire of my Wrath is kindled, and I am Zealous for the ſake of my Word. They imagine Lies, and their Heart is fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led with meer Abomination: But I come
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:38278:62"/>
ſuddenly, O deceitful Generation, that I may ſpew you out, for you are a deadly Poyſon; and that I may make you a Deſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, ſay I the LORD, even the LORD. Obſerve then, dear <hi>Sion,</hi> that the Total Accompliſhment of my Word written by <hi>Joel,</hi> is yet to come. For my Spirit cometh then upon all Fleſh, in a greater meaſure than that in which it came upon my Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles, which was no more than, as it were, a foretaſte of what is yet to be. And then was the fulfilling of it publiſhed, in that manner that it is yet to be done, when even Sucking Children ſhall receive the Spirit to ſuch a degree, as not only to ſee Viſions, but alſo to interpret them. Then ſhall ſuch a Faith appear, as by it greater Works ſhall be wrought, than thoſe which I have wrought: And when one ſaith to the Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, be thou lifted up, and be thou caſt into the Sea; it ſhall be done accordingly. And then will I ſhew ſuch Signs as ye have not yet ſeen, and ſuch as never yet have been in the former Times before you. What ſhould I ſpeak to the Winds, or let my Words be without effect? No, far be it from me. But thoſe who make my Word to lye, and who will not ſuffer it to abide in its ſtrength, muſt come to perdition. Wo to you who Preach but your Ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginations! Let every one take good heed
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:38278:63"/>
to that which he doth: For I am the LORD, and will maintain my Word. But whoſoever would blacken it, or would apply it to his unclean Brutiſh Thoughts, may find it an hard matter to conteſt with me: For I roar as a Lion againſt every A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bomination, and I break forth as Smoke out of the Foreſt, to dry up the falſe Cedars, which without are very beautiful, but with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in are filled with the Abominations of Dogs. Wherefore I have a loathing unto them, and will dreadfully come upon them, and will root them out, and will caſt them in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the deep of the Bottomleſs Pit, where is weeping and gnaſhing of Teeth. But thou O my <hi>Sion,</hi> and <hi>Ephraim</hi> my Beloved, fear not; for I am thy Friend, and I am with thee. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXI.</head>
               <p>Soon after this, the Elect Maid, that ſhe might ſet in order her Domeſtick Affairs upon the Death of her Mother, parted from me, being accompanied with her Siſter. In the mean while a Report was rais'd, how it was I my ſelf that had ſpoken by this Maid, and had made uſe of God's Name to give a colour to that which I pretended to eſtabliſh for a Divine Truth, which had to this time been ſo generally ſpoken againſt; doing herein as <hi>Numa Pompilius</hi> with his Goddeſs <hi>Aegeria,</hi> to make the People of
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:38278:63"/>
                  <hi>Rome</hi> receive that which he himſelf ſpake through her. As this was ſaid to a Perſon of great Quality, he anſwer'd, as I have been inform'd, That the Cheat might eaſily be diſcover'd, by Writing to this Maid, who was then in a Place which was near Four and Twenty <hi>German</hi> Miles remote from me, and propoſing to her ſome Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtions in a Letter that ſhould be Seal'd, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiring her to ſend the ſame back again Seal'd, and together with it an Anſwer. This was accordingly done; and there came an Anſwer in few days to this Perſon of Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity, who was at that time not ſo far di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtant as I was: Whence the Concluſion is evident that it could not be me, but that it muſt be an higher Hand, that ſpake thro' her. The Anſwer is this:</p>
               <p>Peace be with thee; hear my Word, O my Servant. Behold, I am the Spring of Life, and no Body cometh to me, but whom the Father draweth: Therefore give heed to my Word. I purifie and ſanctifie every one, for they are every one in the Father. And I finiſh my Work above all Reaſon; and I repleniſh every thing with Beauty; for I am the Light of the World. I go forth in Sanctification over all, in all the Depths and Breadths; and have no reſpect for Perſons, but my Love is ſpread abroad as a Covering, over Seeds and Seeds, o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:38278:64"/>
                  <note n="(a)" place="margin">Births.</note> Generations to Ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerations: In all Myſterious Deeps my Love paſſeth forth over all. For who is he that can ſound out my Ways and my Wiſdom? Behold I the God of Heaven and Earth go forth in all my Doings, and no Body can comprehend them. I ſee well thy Writings, and even the depths of thine Heart: For before me eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry thing is diſcovered, and laid open. Therefore comprehend thou well my Word, and acknowledge my Wiſdom ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to my meaning. Behold! I JE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>HOVAH have ſaid it, who am made mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt, and am about to Judge the World. I come upon the Wings of the Cherubims; no Body can comprehend me, or know me, but he that is humbled before me. What is it therefore that thou keepeſt in thy Mind, as though thou didſt comprehend it? Verily, verily, I ſay unto thee, even I the Lord; the Lord, that the time cometh, when it ſhall be ſaid, Thou ſhalt know my Name according to my Counſel and my Meaning. I will do it my ſelf in thee: Thou, whom I will form unto me, that thou mayeſt be in me, ſhalt be mine Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment: And many Spirits I do bind together in one, and do teach by my Arm the Divine Generation to Fight. I have loved thee from all time my <hi>Sion,</hi> and dear <hi>Ephraim:</hi>
                  <pb n="83" facs="tcp:38278:64"/>
Be ſtrong as a Lion of <hi>Judah,</hi> and come from the North. I know it, and all things are manifeſt before me, but thou knoweſt not as yet that which I have now ſpoken unto thee: And it is a ſtrange ſaying to thee, and it muſt be ſo till that my Hour is come. Go then in Peace: Thou needeſt not to know any more at preſent; ſtand thou only quiet in my Meekneſs and Patience, and be firmly grounded in my Love which endu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reth for ever, and reſiſt me not. For I am the LORD, who am with thee, and who leave thee not alone: Be then of good Courage, and live well; yea, <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>We alſo receiv'd from the ſame Place an Encouragement, not to conceal the Truth which had been entruſted to us, but to pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh the ſame; to the end that it might be Openly Confeſs'd and Own'd.</p>
               <p>As I live, ſaith the LORD, even I the LORD do ſay it: Return again ye Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of Men: And to the Iſlands I ſay, Fly before my preſence; and to the Rocks, be ye Opened. As I ſit upon the Cherubim and the Seraphim, and rule over all Kings, ſo verily will I make an end of <hi>Edom,</hi> and will root out the Whore of <hi>Babel.</hi> She ſhall eat her ſelf all her Abomination, and all the Storms of her Fury ſhall fall upon her own Head: For ſhe ſitteth and lurketh pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vily
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:38278:65"/>
upon all the Borders, that ſhe may deſtroy<note n="(b)" place="margin">Mode.</note> my Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, which I have beſtowed upon my Daughter of <hi>Sion,</hi> to inſtruct her how to lift up her Eyes toward me, and to ſerve me with all Faithfulneſs. Sit ſtill a little while with patience: For behold I come unto thee ſuddenly, whom I preſerve as the Apple of mine Eye, and I anoint thy Head with Precious Oyl; for thou art mine. He that hath begun, let him remain with the Truth: And he that hath opened his Mouth, let him finiſh it, and not be ſilent; for the perverſeneſs is grown very great: But mine Arm is made more powerful yet, and my Truth overcometh. Watch now, and Believe, for the Hour is come: Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>play the Banners, give a mighty ſhout, and magnifie my Name; for I am in the midſt of you. Yea. <hi>Amen!</hi> Be not fearful, but couragious: For I am your Help and Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory.</p>
               <p>At the ſame time ſhe alſo ſent us from the Place whither ſhe was gone, that which had between Four and Five Years before been dictated to her by the LORD upon the XXth Chapter of the <hi>Revelations,</hi> which has been already Inſerted in the XIth Section. And I can ſay in the preſence of God, that before this time I had never ſeen it with
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:38278:65"/>
mine Eyes, or known in what words it was conceiv'd; although ſhe had made ſome mention in her Mother's Life-time, of her having had for a good while ſuch a Manife<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtation given her.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXII.</head>
               <p>Now as this Elect Maid was upon her Journey to return hither, and ſome Perſons of High Quality in the World, that had been acquainted with her Siſter that was dead, and long heard of the Grace which God had conferr'd upon her, were very deſirous to ſee her; we going out ſome Miles to meet her, were obliged to paſs by that very Place, where theſe Perſons then were. And being by them invited, we went along with Her, and her Siſters to them, and gave them an account of what Extraordinary Gifts God had beſtowed up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Her, and how wonderfully he is pleas'd to reveal himſelf in this laſt Age. Although there were here ſome Gainſayers, yet God left us not without a Bleſſing. For as there aroſe a great deſire to be ſatisfied, whether God, whoſe Mercy is ſo highly extoll'd in the Holy Scriptures, did ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſtingly, and without diſtinction reject the Heathen, and all ſuch, either among the Jews or Chriſtians, as are in a Falſe Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion? And it being ask'd, Whether this Queſtion might be propos'd to the Lord?
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:38278:66"/>
it was done ſo accordingly. And this was the Anſwer which came.</p>
               <p>As Heaven is prepared by my Might, and by my Will; as I am from Everlaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and in me is no Beginning, or End, Beſides what I beget, as it were, in my ſelf, and make a Beginning and an End; ſo true is this my Word, which in Meekneſs and Long-ſuffering I do ſpeak. It is well-pleaſing, and it is my holy Counſel and Will, that Men ſhould believe righteouſly of me, even as I have revealed my ſelf in the Scriptures, when not drawn aſide with one's own Reaſon, but opened with, and by the Holy Ghoſt: who is promiſed to, and reſteth upon all thoſe that are upright in my ſight. As for thoſe who Fight againſt my Truth, with pretence of knowing better, and truſt to the darkneſs of their own imaginary Reaſon, they go down into darkneſs, be they of whatſoever Religion they will. But as many as love me, and ſeek ſeriouſly to be ſanctified by me, not be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing content to believe outwardly, which is without Foundation, or to ſit ſtill with outward Worſhips, but ſearching after me in the Ground of their Hearts, in Spirit and Truth; they find Grace before me, and with me, in all Generations, and in all Religions: If ſo that they do not witting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and after that they are once convinced,
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:38278:66"/>
deny me the Everlaſting Son of the Father. For all muſt go to the Father by me, and all muſt be purified in me; for out of me there is nothing of Purity. The Ignorant let no Man preſume to condemn: for who is there to Judge them but I? And my Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment is Righteous, and for this cauſe they are not judged to Everlaſting Miſery: O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe my Judgment would not be Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teous. Here is the depth of my Secrets: All muſt praiſe me, and be ſubdued to my Truth, and be hallowed and waſhed thro' me: All muſt be put under me, and thro' me be made Righteous in the true acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledgment, that I am the Lord. But how this ſhall be done, and how it ſhall be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compliſhed in the very Heathens, ye are not yet able to comprehend; and therefore I do not explain it to you. This is my word, and the Teſtimony of Truth: For I the Lord, even the Lord JEHOVAH have ſpoken it, who can do beyond all compari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon more than ye are able to comprehend. Watch, for I come.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXIII.</head>
               <p>After ſome days there came to this B. Maid a Principal Officer, who deliver'd to her a Seal'd Letter, which he ſaid came from a Perſon of Quality. The Name of whom he told her, which afterwards was found to be a meer Falſhood, and pray'd
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:38278:67"/>
her to propoſe the ſame, as from the ſaid Perſon, to the Lord. The Anſwer was this;</p>
               <p>I the Lord of Hoſts, who come upon a Cherub, who deſtroy all Falſhood, and root out all Deceitfulneſs; even I it is who ſpeak here. Who is it that perſecuteth me? And who is it that is not diſcovered before me? I ſay unto thee, Repent, A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wake; for it is high time, and I am com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to thee; yea, I come ſpeedily. For my Love and Mercy is great: And to ſuch as have a clean Heart, free from all filthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and dead Works, I am gracious, and hear their Cry, Sighs, and Moans. And Lo! this is my Will, and the Teſtimony which I give to every one, that whoſoever ſhall lay hold on me with a pure Heart, and with a ſtrong Faith, the ſame ſhall at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain to all that remaineth, and ſhall even in all things be able to find it. Yea: <hi>Amen.</hi> I the LORD, even the LORD, who ſpeak with my Voice as the Voice of Thunder, have witneſſed this, and ſpoken this: And there is none that can withſtand me. For I am riſen up, and do many Signs and Wonders: And bleſſed is that Perſon who loveth me, and keepeth my Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; for at the end it ſhall go well with him. See that thou miſtake me not, ſo as to do any thing that may miſlead thee:
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:38278:67"/>
Follow that which is right before me, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording as I do in thy Conſcience witneſs to thee in the Truth, and be godlily-mind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed; and ſo ſhalt thou, with me, be well led, and ſhalt dwell with me in the Light, and not be caſt out into the Darkneſs. This is enough for thee, and I ſay no more.</p>
               <p>A little while after, the aforeſaid Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cer ſent a Letter Seal'd, in his own Name, which the Bleſſed Maid receiv'd, thinking that he had enquir'd ſomething of the Lord, from a remorſe of Conſcience. And this I thought too, for as much as he had fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently ſaid to me, that he wiſh'd to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe with me about God, and in what manner one might advance in Piety: And hence I could not but conclude, that the Lord would give him a gracious Anſwer. But we were ſtruck with a mighty Aſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment, when we read the Lord's fierce Anſwer: Which behold.</p>
               <p>I the LORD have in abhorrence the Blood-guilty, and the Falſe: And he that is Wicked ſhall not ſtand before me. Therefore take away the Evil from before mine Eyes; that this my Word may not become to thee a Terrible Judgment, in the Day of my Wrath: For I am a conſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming Fire.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="90" facs="tcp:38278:68"/>The Elect Virgin made a difficulty of ſending him preſently this dreadful Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony: Whereupon ſhe ſent him back his Letter Sealed, without having open'd it, and wrote to him at the ſame time, that ſhe had receiv'd a very harſh Anſwer, which ſtartled her, the which if he deſir'd to ſee, he might ſend for; which he did the next day. After ſome few days he came to Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſit us, and ſpeaking about the matter of the Letter, he told us what had been in it, which was ſuch a Queſtion, as at which he might for ever bluſh. But he confeſs'd that he had not well done in it: However he endeavour'd to excuſe himſelf with this, that in the firſt Letter, among other Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gions Queſtions, he had demanded ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing concerning the Word <hi>Sacrament;</hi> which having not been exactly anſwer'd to, he did not think it was the Lord who ſpake by her. And this he ſaid was the Reaſon, why he had put ſuch ſort of Queſtions in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the Second Letter; which notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding he wiſh'd he had never done. He alſo confeſs'd that the Firſt Letter was written by himſelf, and not by a Perſon of Quality, as he had before pretended. As we then read over again the Firſt Anſwer, we ſaw clearly that it agreed exactly to him, containing an expreſs mention of Deceit and Falſhood, as alſo that one ought not to
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:38278:68"/>
reſiſt the Lord, to whom all things are diſcover'd, and from whom nothing is hid. Laſtly, That he ſhould take care not to be miſtaken ſo to miſlead himſelf; nor to do any thing which might not ſucceed well with him, or lead him into Evil. So that in the Firſt the Lord would anſwer him not to his Queſtions, but to his Heart: And in the Laſt he hath given him very ſharp menacing words, that ſo he might not per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſt to kick againſt the prickles. God grant that theſe Teſtimonies may pierce into his Heart, that he may be Converted, and do true Repentance.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXIV.</head>
               <p>Upon this Encounter the B. Maid be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came ſomewhat more reſerv'd, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolv'd not to receive for the future any Letter that ſhould be Seal'd, from any Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon whatſoever; ſince ſhe muſt do it in doubt, and could not know whether it be writ from an Heart that is upright and humbled before God, or not. She there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore neither would, nor could, after this unpleaſant Experience, propoſe to the Lord the Treachery and Abomination of any one elſe. And concluded not to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe to Him any thing, but what ſhould proceed from an humble Heart, wanting to be ſatisfied. And in this Reſolution ſhe
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:38278:69"/>
hath been Confirm'd by the Lord him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf; who ſpake to her in this manner.</p>
               <p>I am Holy; therefore let every one that cometh to Ask of me, examine himſelf well whether he be likewiſe of a clean Heart: And if not, let him not think that I ſhould viſit him in my Word to Anſwer him. For this end hold thou to Me, for I will not that thy Righteous Soul ſhould be importuned by the impure Wretches of this World. Go out from their Abominations, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive not any thing at all from them: For I am the LORD. Nay even thoſe who love Me, if they come not to me in a Child-like and Humble Heart, they ſhall not be heard by me. Let every one that dareth to lift up his Eyes toward me, come himſelf to me with his Heart, and not by Letter; and I will anſwer him willingly, and will not ſhut him out. I go before in Love: For hitherto have I ſpoken in patience, but they would make an ill uſe of it, and would make thee to ſin without thy knowledge. Break then the Cords, and ſuffer not thy ſelf to be bound, and take nothing from them, but only from ſuch as are true-hearted and humble: Such will I hear, when they complain; and will anſwer, when they enquire not out of Curioſity.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="93" facs="tcp:38278:69"/>Now although the Lord will not An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer ſuch Curious Enquirers, and She San<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctify'd and Purify'd in the Blood of Chriſt, will not admit of ſuch like Queſtions; yet nevertheleſs He was the very ſame day ſo Good, as to give us that which follows.</p>
               <p>Courage My <hi>SION!</hi> thou dear <hi>Shula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mite</hi> ſhalt now go ſuddenly forth out of <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bylon.</hi> I will give to thee the Wings of Righteouſneſs, that thou mayeſt fly away from the Abomination of <hi>Babel:</hi> Thou ſhalt have no Communion with her, that ſo thou mayeſt not be polluted. For I will have thee to be clean, and without Spot: I will cloath thee with the Saphir, and will Crown thee with Righteouſneſs. For thou haſt been rudely treated, and thy Wounds have been very bad; but now it is all over. For the Vine beginneth to put forth its Branches, and I take pleaſure in my Bride; for ſhe is become lovely in my Eyes: Therefore will I deck her with Light and Glory, without meaſure, and ſhe ſhall find that I deal kindly with her. Let then the <hi>Babylonian</hi> Wicked inſult over you with all their might: Be ye not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mayed hereat; I am your Buckler, your Defence, and your Armour; and with Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice I cover you as with a Garment. I the LORD am arming my ſelf to fight for you with a Mighty Arm: For now is the time
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:38278:70"/>
that Light and Darkneſs muſt be ſeparated from each other; that ſo <hi>SION</hi> may dwell before Me. And verily, the Cherubs with Thrones and Principalities are in Array to Fight for <hi>Sion</hi> againſt <hi>Babel.</hi> But take this in a right Senſe: The Battel is for the ſake of <hi>Sion</hi>'s Spirit, that her Cauſe may be ſtrengthn'd and made certain, and that there may be a Separation from the Works of <hi>Babel.</hi> For this end it is time that ye watch, and ſtand upon your Guards Night and Day: For I come, and do ſound all the Depths. And therefore I witneſs thus, and will witneſs in all Languages and Tongues, and will pour out my Spirit largely, and adorn my Bride as to the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage-feaſt, yea, as to the Triumph. She ſhall cry aloud for Joy, and magnifie my Name aforehand. When all this ſhall be tranſacted before in the Spirit, then ſhall the Decree, (or Curſe) come forth againſt <hi>Babel:</hi> And <hi>Sion</hi> ſhall then be as an Armed Man, and I as a Roaring Lion, againſt <hi>Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bel</hi> and all her Abominations: And then ſhall the Jdugment be revealed and come forth. Wo to you ye Earthly-minded Men when I come. Of whom is that ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing true, That I ſhall not find Faith upon the Earth. But Bleſſed are the Simple and the Children, for unto ſuch doth the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom belong. Therefore be ſtill, reſt in
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:38278:70"/>
humility, and fear not; for I am before you. Again I ſay, Bleſſed are the little Children; for of ſuch is the Kingdom of Heaven: Yea, yea, <hi>Amen!</hi> ſay I the Lord of Lords, the God and Saviour in the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of theſe Children. Wherefore ſtudy that you may become like to them; and ſo ſhall ye be made all Light. Rejoice ye, for the Victory is to <hi>Sion.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXV.</head>
               <p>Before I conſider the Queſtions, I ſhall from ſome Paſſages of holy Scripture ſuc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cinctly prove, that God never declar'd it to be his Will that there ſhould be no more Apparitions or Revelations, after our Saviours Aſcenſion; but that on the contrary he hath given expreſs Promiſes in his Word, that before the Dreadful Day of the Lord, he will ſend forth his Scribes Learned in the Kingdom of Heaven, his Wiſemen and Prophets for a Warning to the World, and for an Encouragement to his Faithful Servants. Neither have we a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny room for Doubt, as to the Divinity of theſe Viſions and Revelations; if once it appear, that the Lord, according to his ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Purpoſe, and Will, doth really, and according to the Rules laid down by Mr. <hi>Fabricius,</hi> Superintendent-General of <hi>Pome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rania,</hi>
                  <pb n="96" facs="tcp:38278:71"/>
in his Diſcourſe<note n="*" place="margin">De Probatione Viſionum.</note> 
                  <hi>of the Trial of Viſions,</hi> give to his Children in all Ages of the Church ſuch Manifeſtations as theſe. Of which the ſaid Author has Collected together a great number of Examples from Approv'd Fathers, Doctors, and other Writers.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXVI.</head>
               <p>That God therefore <hi>will</hi> (for that he <hi>may</hi> if he <hi>will,</hi> I ſuppoſe there is no Divine will deny) grant ſuch like Apparitions, and extraordinary Revelations, I prove firſt from the Prophet <hi>Joel,</hi> Chap. 2. of which take this brief Account. Now that the Contents of this Chapter have never yet been Accompliſh'd ſince the time of <hi>Joel,</hi> will be put out of all Diſpute. The time in which he Propheſied is not expreſs'd, but however certain it is that it was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Captivity of <hi>Babylon.</hi> Let us then ſee whether the Propheſie contain'd in this Chapter, can have had its fulfulling, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in the Calamity which the City of <hi>Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruſalem,</hi> and the People of the <hi>Jews</hi> ſuffer'd by <hi>Nebuchadnezzar,</hi> or in that other brought upon them by <hi>Titus Veſpaſian.</hi> Now it is certain by theſe Verſes, <hi>viz.</hi> 1, 7, 9, and 11. that when this Chapter muſt have its Accompliſhment, then Mount <hi>Sion</hi> muſt be in a good Eſtate, and the City of <hi>Jeruſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem,</hi>
                  <pb n="97" facs="tcp:38278:71"/>
with its Temple, be ſtanding. More<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>over in <hi>ver.</hi> 2. a Day, which is call'd the Day of the Lord, is deſcrib'd as a Day of Darkneſs, and of Gloomineſs, of Clouds, and of thick Darkneſs: And this ſhall here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in conſiſt, that a mighty and ſtrong People, of whom there has not been ever the like, neither ſhall be any more to all Eternity; ſhall come upon <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> as the Morning ſpread upon the Mountains. Now that this cannot be ſaid of the <hi>Babyloniſh</hi> Army, name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, that it was a People ſo Mighty, as there hath never been the like of them, nor ever ſhall be again in all Generations, or to all Eternity; will eaſily be granted by all the World. And that this cannot be under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtood here of the <hi>Roman</hi> Army, is no leſs evident. For thoſe that pretend this Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter is already fulfill'd, muſt at the ſame time own, that if the Holy Ghoſt, in <hi>ver.</hi> 28. was poured out in the firſt <hi>Pentecoſt,</hi> and if the <hi>Romans</hi> did not Beſiege and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> but till Forty Years after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward, it is impoſſible that in the Second Verſe mention could be made of this Army. From the Third Verſe to the Ninth, the manner in which this Army ſhall March is deſcrib'd. In the Tenth it is ſaid, That the Earth ſhall quake before it, the Heavens tremble, the Sun and the Moon be dark, and the Stars withdraw their ſhining. In
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:38278:72"/>
the Eleventh, the Lord utters his Voice be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore His Army, which ſhall be very great and ſtrong, and ſhall execute his Word, in ſuch wiſe, that this Day of the Lord ſhall be a Day ſo great, and ſo terrible, that none ſhall be able to abide it. That all this ſhould be done by the <hi>Babylonian</hi> Army is not probable, either from Scripture, or from any other Writer; and much leſs by the <hi>Roman,</hi> to which the very Order of the Prophet, will not permit us to apply it, as hath been already ſaid. From the Twelfth to the Sixteenth Verſe, the Prophet gives Counſel, how the Inhabitants of <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> ought to behave themſelves, and what they ought to do to be exempted from the Cala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mity. Which beſides can have no manner of Application to the <hi>Babylonian</hi> Expediti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, ſince it was known out of the Prophet, that not only at that time there would not be any Remedy, but that the <hi>Jews</hi> were bound according to God's Will, to ſurren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der themſelves up to the <hi>Babylonians;</hi> which ſince they refus'd to do, the King, toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther with the Nobles, made hereby the Miſery to fall heavier upon themſelves, their City, and their People, and ſo drew down upon themſelves their own Ruin. In the 17th He proſecutes his Counſel, by ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſing the Prieſts, the Miniſters of the Lord, to weep between the Porch and the Altar,
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:38278:72"/>
and to ſay, <hi>Spare thy People, O Lord, and give not thine Heritage to reproach, that the Heathen ſhould rule over them: Wherefore wilt thou let it be a By-word amongſt the Nations, Where is their God?</hi> Hereupon follows in the 18th Verſe till the 27th, the Anſwer of this Prayer, namely, that God would be Jealous for his Land, and pity his People. Now it is not found that either the Prieſts then made ſuch a Prayer betwixt the Porch and the Altar; or that the Anſwer, which is here promis'd to ſuch a Prayer, did fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low: The <hi>Temple,</hi> with the whole City of <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> and the Land of <hi>Canaan</hi> being deſtroy'd and made deſolate. Neither did this at all come to paſs in the Deſtruction from the <hi>Romans,</hi> but the Temple was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd to Aſhes ſome Weeks before the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and then there follow'd not any Relief, but ſuch a Deſolation as endureth yet to this very day. Nay, the Order which the Prophet obſerves, will not at all permit, as hath been ſaid already, that the Deſtruction of <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> by the <hi>Romans</hi> ſhould be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply'd hereto: Since that which now fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lows in the Text, muſt according to the Sentiment of thoſe who believe this Prophe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſie already fulfill'd, have been Forty Years before the Deſtruction of <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> which nevertheleſs the Prophet puts after the Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lamity, which he deſcribes here, and which
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:38278:73"/>
ſhall come upon <hi>Jeruſalem.</hi> For after that this ſhall be, after that <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> ſhall be Environ'd, after that it's Walls ſhall be Scal'd, and after that the Enemies ſhall be as it were Maſters of the City: After that the People ſhall be hereby Converted to the Lord, and after that the Prieſts ſhall ſend up to Him their Groans and Supplications, and that He ſhall hear theſe Groans and theſe Supplications, ſhall ſpare his Land, and his People, ſhall repel the Enemies, and laſtly, ſhall cauſe them to ſee again, and to enjoy much Proſperity; then will the Lord, after all this, pour out his Spirit upon all Fleſh, and the Sons, and the Daughters ſhall Propheſie, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Now this having not come to paſs upon the <hi>Babylonian</hi> Captivity and Deſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, and yet much leſs upon the <hi>Roman;</hi> and ſince that which after this Promiſe happen'd in <hi>Pentecoſt</hi> to the Apoſtles, pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeded the latter by many Years; it is cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, that the Prophetical Text has not hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto had its Total Accompliſhment to this preſent day, but that neceſſarily the Time, wherein it muſt and ſhall be accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſh'd, is yet to come; it being impoſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble for the Word to Lie. And this is alſo Confirm'd by the Third Chapter, whoſe Coherence with the Second is indiſſoluble, that <hi>in thoſe days, and in that time,</hi> when that which is promis'd in the Second Chapter ſhall be fulfill'd, he (the Lord) <hi>ſhall bring
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:38278:73"/>
again the Captivity of</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſalem: In which nevertheleſs <hi>Judah</hi> and <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> have, ſince the pouring out of the Holy Spirit upon the Day of <hi>Pentecoſt,</hi> been al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready more than Sixteen Hundred Years, and ſtill are in it. Beſides there is alſo ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſs'd ſuch a Promiſe in the 28th and 29th Verſes of the Second Chapter, which could not be Accompliſh'd in the Apoſtles, ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that after this the Spirit ought to be pour'd out upon all Fleſh, in ſuch a manner, as that their Sons and Daughters ſhould Propheſie, their Old Men ſhould dream Dreams, and their Boys ſhould ſee Viſions, and that alſo in thoſe days upon their Men-ſervants, and upon their Maid-ſervants, ſhould the Spirit be poured out. Now the Apoſtles are not <hi>all Fleſh:</hi> And much leſs can it be ſaid of them that they are call'd Sons and Daughters, Boys, Men-ſervants and Maid-ſervants, and at the very ſame time likewiſe Old Men. It is true, that in the Firſt <hi>Pentecoſt</hi> of the New Teſtament, there came upon the Apoſtles that which the Lord hath here promis'd, yet this was very far from fulfilling the Propheſie: This was only a Beginning, and a Foretaſte, of which the Total Accompliſhment is yet to be expected. And this is alſo ſufficient<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly evident from the very words of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtle <hi>Peter, Acts</hi> 2.39. that the Promiſe was
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:38278:74"/>
to them, and to their Children, and to all that were afar, whom the Lord our God ſhould call. Wherefore ſince the Day here deſcrib'd, even the Terrible Day of the Lord, is not yet come, nor ſhall come, but in the time of the Sixth Seal, <hi>Rev.</hi> 6. And ſince the effectual Deliverance of God has not, according to what has been alrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy prov'd, been given upon the Prayers of the Prieſts in the time of the Captivity of <hi>Babylon,</hi> or of the Deſtruction of <hi>Jeruſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem:</hi> Which Deliverance ought neverthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs to be effected at the ſame time, with the Fact here deſcrib'd by <hi>Joel,</hi> in ſuch a man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner, that God will appear Jealous for his People, and will pity them: And in the third place, ſince that to this preſent day the Captivity of <hi>Judah,</hi> and of <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> is not turn'd away, nor all the Heathens judged, and much leſs in the Valley of <hi>Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hoſaphat, Joel</hi> 3.2, 9, 10, 11, 12. which the 14th Chapter of the <hi>Revelations,</hi> com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>par'd with the Third of this Prophet, <hi>ver.</hi> 13. lays down as a thing which ought yet to come: And laſtly, ſince the 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, and 21 Verſes, are not hitherto in their power executed, namely, that <hi>Jeru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem</hi> ſhall be Holy, and that no Stranger ſhall paſs through her any more; but that <hi>Judah</hi> ſhall abide for ever, and <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> from Generations to Generations: It is not
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:38278:74"/>
to be doubted, upon all theſe Conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, but that God will according to his Promiſe, <hi>After that time I will pour out my Spirit upon all Fleſh,</hi> cauſe ſuch Viſions, Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſies and Revelations as are here de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcrib'd, effectually to be in this Latter Time; in like manner, as he hath by many Powerful Teſtimonies witneſs'd to the ſame, by the Elect Virgin, and confirm'd us in the expectation of its future Comple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXVII.</head>
               <p>In the Holy <hi>Revelation</hi> of Jeſus Chriſt, (for this ought to be the Title of that Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Book, according to <hi>Chap.</hi> 1. where it is ſaid, That God gave this <hi>Revelation</hi> unto Jeſus Chriſt, to ſhew unto his Servants) there is alſo found a clear Argument of God's Will; that he will ſend his Two Witneſſes, Adorn'd with very many ſingu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Powers, true Miracles, and conſequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly many Extraordinary Gifts; who ſhall Propheſie Twelve Hundred and Sixty Days, <hi>Rev.</hi> 11.3, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> This is done in the <hi>Fifth Seal,</hi> in which their Companions, and they both at the laſt, when they ſhall have fi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd their Teſtimony, ſhall be kill'd, and after Three Days and an Half, ſhall tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and bodily riſe again, to the Terrour of their Enemies, and aſcend up to Heaven in the Clouds, their Enemies beholding them.
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:38278:75"/>
Now that this has not been hitherto Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compliſh'd is evident, in that the Miracles which are here ſpecify'd, as for inſtance, That they ſhould go forth in the Power of <hi>Moſes</hi> and of <hi>Elias,</hi> and cauſe Fire to fall from Heaven, and turn the Waters into Blood, and ſhut Heaven for the ſpace of Three Years and an Half (as did <hi>Elias, Jam.</hi> 4.) to the end it rain not; have not been yet ſeen. Beſides the Judgment which follows after the Twelve Hundred and Threeſcore Days, is not yet come, which ſhall be at the <hi>Second Wo,</hi> in the <hi>Sixth Trum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pet:</hi> After which ſhall quickly ſucceed the <hi>Third Wo</hi> of the Seven Vials of Wrath, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Seven laſt Plagues in the <hi>Seventh Trumpet;</hi> and ſhall make an end of <hi>Baby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lon,</hi> and of the Enemies of God, to the glorious bringing forth of a Better Time; of which it is ſaid, <hi>Now are the Kingdoms of the World, become the Kingdoms of the LORD, and of his CHRIST:</hi> And alſo, <hi>We give thee thanks, O Lord God Almighty, who art, and waſt, and art to come, becauſe thou haſt taken to thy ſelf great Power and Domini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, Rev.</hi> 11.15, 17. Whereas at this time <hi>Babylon</hi> is ſtanding in its full Vigour; there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Witneſſes are ſtill to come. But about the time that <hi>Babylon</hi> ſhall be Judg'd, the Two Witneſſes which are ſent by Chriſt, ſhall before give their Teſtimony
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:38278:75"/>
by Propheſies and Miracles, according to God's Promiſe, in which his Will is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained.</p>
               <p>That God ſhould do ſuch Miracles as theſe in the Laſt Time, was both foreſeen and believ'd by that dear Man of God <hi>Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther,</hi> who in his Commentary upon the Firſt Book of <hi>Moſes,</hi> thus delivers himſelf; <note n="(a)" place="margin">Poſtquam <hi>Noah</hi> &amp; fui diu clamaverunt, acccuſantes malitiam Mundi, oſtendit tandem Dominus, ſe quoque il<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lam malitiam videre, &amp; ulciſci velle. Hunc ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cundum gradum nos quoque Hodie expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mus, nec dubium eſt, quin erunt ALIQUI HOMINES, <hi>quibus re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velabitur iſta mundi per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditio futura.</hi> Niſi forte ea perditio erit dies no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſſimus &amp; extremum judicium, quod ſane op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tamus. <hi>Et Lat. f. m.</hi> 122. <hi>a.</hi>
                  </note> 
                  <q>When <hi>Noah</hi> and his Sons had a long while Preach'd, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuſing the Wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the World, the Lord at laſt ſhews, that he alſo ſaw the Wickedneſs, and would revenge it. This in ſome Degree we alſo at this day expect: Nor is it to be doubted, but that there will be SOME PERSONS, <hi>to whom this Future Deſtruction of the World ſhall be reveal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</hi> Unleſs perhaps this Deſtruction may be the Laſt Day, and the Final Judgment, which we indeed do hope.</q> And in his
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:38278:76"/>
Preface upon <hi>Amos</hi> he ſays;<note n="(b)" place="margin">Hic mos eſt Do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mino Deo noſtro, ut, quoties inſignis aliqua rerum mutatio inſtat, quoties egregium ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quod malum imminet, mittat Prophetas ſuos, aut Miniſtros verbi, qui verbum nuncient, qui futura mala praedicent; ut ſaltem Aliqui con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertantur, &amp; ad poeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tentiam reducantur. <hi>Tom.</hi> III. <hi>Jen. Lat.</hi>
                  </note> 
                  <q>This is the manner with the Lord our God, as often as any Signal Revolution is at hand, or any nota<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Evil doth im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend, to ſend his Prophets and Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of his Word, who may Preach the Word, and Foretel the Evils that are to come; that ſome at leaſt may be Converted, and Call'd to Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pentance.</q> Alſo in the <hi>German</hi> Edition of his Works, he hath the<note n="(c)" place="margin">Tom. IX. Edit. <hi>Wittemberg. Germ.</hi> f. m. 268, 269, ſeq.</note> Viſion con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the Pope, which happen'd in <hi>Switzerland</hi> to Friar <hi>Nicolas Van Felſen,</hi> and was before written by <hi>Charles de Bouillon;</hi> and he hath made to it a Preface, to ſhew in what manner we ought to make Reflecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on upon ſuch Signs and Miracles, which Chriſt hath given to the Papacy. And do we not alſo read in the <hi>Confeſſion of Ausbourg,</hi> as in Our Symbolical or Canonical Book, the<note n="(d)" place="margin">Apolog. Aug. Conf. <hi>De Votis Mona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſticis.</hi>
                  </note> Propheſie of <hi>John</hi> of <hi>Hilten,</hi> how
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:38278:76"/>
that in the Year MDXVI. there ſhould come one that ſhould Preach againſt the Diſorder of the Monks; which was ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fill'd accordingly in <hi>Luther?</hi> So alſo the Clergy of <hi>Lubeck, Hambourg,</hi> and <hi>Lunen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burg,</hi> in their <hi>Apology againſt the Patron, of the Revelation of Guthman,</hi> would not at all declare that they did<note n="(e)" place="margin">Part. 1. p. 84, &amp;c. 269.297.</note> Simply and Ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolutely reject and condemn all Viſions and Revelations of theſe Times. <hi>Baldwi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nus</hi> confirms the ſame with theſe Words;<note n="(f)" place="margin">Non dubitamus Deum Adhuc nonnullis interdum revelare Fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tura, quae ad Eccleſiae &amp; Reipub. ſtatum per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinent, in uſum homi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num annuntianda. <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. ſup. Ep.</hi> 1. <hi>Tim.</hi> 4. <hi>p.</hi> 251.</note> 
                  <q>We do not doubt that God doth yet ſometimes re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veal to Some Future Things pertaining to Church and State, which are to be De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clar'd for the Good of Men.</q> There are alſo other Divines of Authority, who aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſert the ſame thing, whom we omit; as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to be found in the aforeſaid <hi>Fabricius.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXVIII.</head>
               <p>For a Concluſion, I ſhall yet add here one Conſiderable Teſtimony, which we re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd from the Lord, by this Bleſſed Lady,
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:38278:77"/>
this preſent Year MDCXCI. And it is this.</p>
               <p>Dear Friends, peace be with you: Stir up one another in my Love, and give me your Heart wholly; to the end I may dwell in it with all my Fulneſs: And have no fear then, for I am your Defence, and your Shield, and my Loving-kindneſs I will not turn away from you, but will fill you with good things. I will give you to drink of Pleaſure, I will ſanctifie the baſhful, I will take care of the feeble, I will refreſh the weary, and will keep mine Eye upon thoſe that are unſtable; for I am the Everlaſting Love and Friendſhip. From me proceed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the Light, for I am the Light of the World; and whoſoever cometh to me muſt walk in the Light, and have in him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf the Works of the Light, and depart from that which is unclean. Make ready to divert me, O my Siſter, who art to me as a rich Odour: Drive away every thing that hindereth thee; and be cheerful. Paſs mightily on, let nothing ſtop thee, O Daughter of <hi>Sion;</hi> for behold, I gird thy Loins with Truth: Let thy Marching be ſtately, as the little Hills of God, and let my Voice be to thee a Melodious Sound, that thou mayeſt go leaping with ſure ſteps, with ſhouts of Joy, and great Acclamati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, to embrace me in the way, where I
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:38278:77"/>
wait for thee. Come then, my Dove, O thou Godly one, who art clean, chaſte, and ſpotleſs: For thou art eſcaped from out of the Abominations of <hi>Babylon,</hi> and all her Darkneſs is to thee abominable, and her Deeds loathſom. Ah! How ſhall I ſufficiently expreſs, how exceedingly I now love thee, when I am become one Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit with thee? Now are we made one, now is my Love fill'd up in thee, my whole Heart floweth into thee, I ſhine in thee, and my Glory beholdeth it ſelf in thee as in a Glaſs. Such is my Spouſe, ſuch is my Fair One, as the very Angels long to behold her. Behold, how thou haſt wounded mine Heart! I am thine, and thou art mine. In this manner do I comprehend in One, all that are fled out from the accurſed Works of <hi>Babel,</hi> and are of pure Hearts. This is the Dove, this is the Beloved, as it ſhall be filled up and glorified. Wherefore be not at all caſt down, ye who have the Heart pure: I will make to you an Help, which <hi>Babel</hi> ſhall not be able to reſiſt: Yea, I will make it, even I the Lord, the LORD. For I ſee your Hunger and Thirſt, after my Righteouſneſs, and your loathing of the Works of <hi>Babel.</hi> Therefore will I be good unto you, and will ſtrengthen your Courage, that you may have no Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munion with the Whore, or be defiled
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:38278:78"/>
with her Uncleanneſs. Labour then, that with Indignation againſt her, ye may be freed from the filthineſs, which it may be do yet ſtick to the Soles of your Feet: and caſt her Whoriſh Works into her Eyes, to the end that her ſhame may fall upon her Head, and that I may force her to eat up her own Abominations. For I will over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn her, ſay I the Lord, the LORD; yea, I will overturn her, and will recom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence it upon her own Head. Thoſe at whom ſhe now laugheth, ſhall recompence her ſhame, diſhonour, deriſion and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt, Tenfold in her Boſom; for I the Lord, the LORD, have ſpoken it. And againſt you, ye Fooliſh Daughters, I ſay this: Ye hope in vain, your hope ſhall va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh, for I will ſhut the Door againſt you. Believe ye that you have ſtill time to riſe up? What mean you to cloath your ſelves in my Robe, and to do the Luſts of the Fleſh in the Faith, and to have ſtill de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>light in the ſecret Pleaſures of <hi>Babylon?</hi> Why inſult ye over me? Think ye that I do not ſee your Works? How is it that ye look upon me with one Eye, and turn the other to <hi>Babel;</hi> and yet would con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrain me, and go in unto me? Verily I ſay unto you, I will make you Aſham'd, and will ſhut the Door againſt you, and turn you away. Obſerve this well, and flatter
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:38278:78"/>
not your ſelves, then ſhall it be well with you: This is what I ſay and ſwear to you.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XXXIX.</head>
               <p>From hence may ariſe this Queſtion in the firſt place: Suppoſing that to any one among you it hath happen'd, or ſhould hereafter happen, that which hath hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen'd to me, as that he ſhould receive in his Heart, a powerful and convincing Reſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lution from God's Prophetical Word, as it is contain'd in the Scripture, concerning the Laſt Times, and the Thouſand Years Reign of Chriſt, with all that depends upon it; and that then afterward he ſhould receive from God, by a moſt precious Inſtrument of his, a very clear Teſtimony in Writing, with full Conviction of Heart, that he had rightly comprehended from the Scripture the Truth of this Kingdom, and of the Judgments impending upon the World, to the leading forth the Children of God; and that he ought to declare the ſame before all the World; how is he oblig'd to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>have himſelf in this Caſe, and whether he ought to be ſuſpicious of ſo Powerful a Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony, and to avoid the Contradictions and Slanders of Men, abſtain from it, as from a Diabolical Deluſion?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XL.</head>
               <p>In the ſecond place, the Queſtion is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Divine Revelations in general,
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:38278:79"/>
without reſpect had to this Matter of Fact in Particular. About which notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, we ſhall in the end add ſome Queſtions to be Reſolv'd.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Query</hi> I. Whether Chriſt after his Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſion, would not Reveal himſelf any more in the Latter Time to any of his Faithful Servants, ſeeing that ſince that he appear'd both to <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Stephen,</hi> and gave his Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Revelation to the Beloved <hi>John</hi> after his Aſcenſion: what Ground is there to think, that Divine Revelations ſhould be no more after that time?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> II. Whether from that paſſage, <hi>Heb.</hi> 1.1, 2. that God after having at ſundry Times, and in diverſe Manners ſpoken to the Patriarchs and Prophets, hath laſtly ſpoken to us by his Son; it can be prov'd that <hi>Chriſt,</hi> after having reveal'd to us in the Fleſh, the Will and Counſel of his Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, will no more reveal himſelf for the future? And whether this be not meant on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly of the Glory of the Revelation of God in the Laſt Time, that after the Accompliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the time prepared according to his Purpoſe, he has been pleas'd, Laſtly to ſpeak to us by his Son come in the Fleſh? And whether in ſuch manner it will not ra<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ther follow from this place, that, ſince God
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:38278:79"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>th Reveal'd himſelf more gloriouſly in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e New, than in the Old Teſtament, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ording as the Number of the Paſt Days en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>reaſes, as to this World, and the time of Reſtitution or Refreſhment in the future World daily draws nearer, the Revelation <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>f God will daily encreaſe in the Prelude <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>f the Approaching Glory? For if by <hi>Laſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>,</hi> or <hi>in theſe laſt Times,</hi> be underſtood, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hat God after having ſpoken to us by his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>on, would no more Reveal himſelf to Mankind, would it not thence follow, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Apoſtles Doctrine might be juſtly ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected, in as much as they had, after the time of <hi>Chriſt</hi>'s being here in the Fleſh, ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Revelations; and would not St. <hi>Paul</hi> have thus written againſt himſelf?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> III. Whether that paſſage, <hi>Luke</hi> 16.29. <hi>They have</hi> Moſes <hi>and the Prophets,</hi> &amp;c. be an Argument to reject abſolutely the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velations of this Day? And whether if this be a true Proof, the Apoſtles themſelves ought not to have been ſuſpicious of their own Divine Revelations, in as much as they were receiv'd, after that <hi>Moſes</hi> and the Prophets were already inſerted in the H. Scripture?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> IV. Whence could <hi>Abraham, Jacob, Moſes, Elias,</hi> the reſt of the Prophets, the
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:38278:80"/>
Apoſtles, and others, whom we read of in the Scripture, to have had Divine Reve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations; know infallibly, and without dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of being deceiv'd, their Revelations to be Divine? Particularly how could <hi>Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> who had theſe Revelations, before even one written Word, according to which he might examine them, had been given?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> V. Whence is it then that you, who ſay, that you own for Divine, the Word which was given to the aforeſaid Holy Men, can be aſſur'd that you are not Miſtaken in them?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> VI. Whether if one receive the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Scripture for an Infallible Truth, there be any reaſon to reject as Diabolical a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>velation, which is in no part contrary to the ſaid Scripture, yea, which corrobo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rates it, and gives Teſtimony to the ſame thing with it? And whether it be proba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble that the Devil, of whoſe caſting down, Deſtruction and Binding the Scripture bears Record, ſhould reveal any thing himſelf, concerning the Approach of the Deſtruction of his Kingdom? Or ſhould do any thing to encourage a Faithful Soul, to arm her ſelf againſt him with the Power of God?</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="115" facs="tcp:38278:80"/>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> VII. Whether it be not dangerous to look on All Revelation, ſimply as ſuch, to be Diabolical at this time? And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther this be not an attributing greater Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour to the Devil, than to God himſelf? And what one ought to judge concerning thoſe Preachers, who being call'd <hi>Lutheran,</hi> and of the <hi>Auguſtane</hi> Confeſſion, do never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theleſs reject publickly in the Pulpit, and even upon Common Fame, without the leaſt Examination of the Truth, decry as Diabolical, ſuch as neither <hi>Luther,</hi> or the <hi>Auguſtane</hi> Confeſſion have ſimply rejected? As may appear from ſeveral Writings of <hi>Luther,</hi> and from the <hi>Apology</hi> of the <hi>Augu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtane Confeſſion,</hi> which expreſly cites the Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions of one <hi>Hiltenius.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> VIII. Whether it ought not to be believ'd, that when a Soul hath a true Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vine Revelation, it ſhall receive alſo from God an Infallible Token, that this Revelati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on comes from him; ſince St. <hi>Paul</hi> ſays, <hi>We may know the things which are given to us of God,</hi> 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 2.12. And St. <hi>John, We</hi> know <hi>that we are of God,</hi> 1 <hi>John</hi> 5.19. And likewiſe, <hi>We are of God, and he that</hi> knoweth <hi>God, heareth us; but he that is not of God, heareth not us: Hereby</hi> know <hi>we the Spirit of Truth, and the Spirit of Errour,</hi> 1 <hi>John</hi> 4.6.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="116" facs="tcp:38278:81"/>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> IX. Whether to ſay, That God will not give to the Soul, to whom he Reveals himſelf, ſome Certain Token of Trial, whereby the ſaid Perſon (as ſome have written) may be able to diſtinguiſh, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the Inſpiration, or the Voice, which he either in the Spirit, or by the Outward Ear, doth hear, be from God, or from the Devil, be any ways reconcileable with God's Love for Mankind? And whether he would ever have had any Reaſon to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand us to beware of Seducers, and Falſe Prophets, when according to this Suppoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, we could not be capable to diſcern, whether the Apparitions were from God, or the Devil? And how, I pray you, ſhall the Two Witneſſes, whom God, according to <hi>Rev.</hi> 11. will ſend, come one day to be acknowledg'd; ſince the very Falſe Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets ſhall do ſo great Miracles, and with ſo near a reſemblance of the Truth? <hi>Mat.</hi> 24.2. <hi>Theſ.</hi> 2.9. <hi>Rev.</hi> 13.13, 14, 15, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> X. If there be no more any Divine Revelation, it may be demanded, Why doth God therefore ſay by <hi>Amos,</hi> That he <hi>will do nothing, but he revealeth his Secrets unto his Servants the Prophets?</hi> If it be ſaid, That this has been already done, I deſire to know, where are to be found in the Scripture, all the Particulars of the Great Acts of God in
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:38278:81"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Laſt Time? Or if they are found, is it not certain at leaſt, that there are in the ſame Prophetical Word, which is acknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledged for Divine, a great many things yet Reſerv'd and Seal'd up? See <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.4. <hi>Rev.</hi> 10.4. ſo as the Prophets themſelves ſometimes have not underſtood what was given to them, <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.8. Since there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore according to the Plain Promiſe of God, <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.4. Knowledge in the Propheſies ſhall in the Time of the End, be open'd to many, I deſire to know, Whether God ſhall not, according as the time of their Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compliſhment draws near, give a Revelati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to ſeveral, even of this obſcure Word of Propheſie, either by a Reſolution from the Word it ſelf, or from other Extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Teſtimonies? And to this, that which is ſaid, <hi>Rev.</hi> 22.10. hath an expreſs Rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> XI. Whether God, who hath always choſen that which is Weak before the World, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 1.27. may not alſo in theſe Days beſtow his Revelations, even upon the Weaker Sex? And whether all that comes from a Woman, ſhould on that account be rejected? Since that God Reveal'd himſelf to <hi>Hannah, Mary,</hi> the Daughters of <hi>Phi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lip,</hi> and many others; and ſince that he hath alſo by <hi>Joel,</hi> expreſly promis'd the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:38278:82"/>
Gifts of the Spirit, to the <hi>Hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maidens,</hi> and to the <hi>Daughters;</hi> which Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie has not hitherto in its full extent been Accompliſh'd, as was prov'd, Section XXXVI.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> XII. Whether as many as Cavil with theſe Extraordinary Gifts in the Female Sex, do not indeed condemn King <hi>Joſiah,</hi> and the High-Prieſt <hi>Hilkiah,</hi> for having pray'd the Propheteſs <hi>Huldah,</hi> to enquire of the Lord, concerning the Matter which was then before them? And if on the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary, theſe Great and Holy Men did well, where then is the good of ſpeaking ſo diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>advantageouſly of them at this Day, when it is indiſputable, that God hath to ſome of this Sex, communicated ſuch like Extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary Gifts? See 2 <hi>Chron.</hi> 34.20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>XLI.</head>
               <p>In the Third place, the Queſtion is concerning this Matter of Fact in Particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> 1. Whether it be poſſible for the Love and Faithfulneſs of God, ever to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mit, that a Perſon ſo Innocent as this Young Lady, who never, either out of Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual Pride or Curioſity, deſir'd ſuch Graces as theſe; but to whom, without de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiring,
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:38278:82"/>
they were freely given by God, from her very Childhood; and who in the whole Courſe of her Life demonſtrates the Senſe which ſhe hath of Chriſt, hates the Works of the Devil, and every thing that is Wicked, and loves God with all her Heart; whether, I ſay, it be poſſible for him to ſuffer, that ſuch a Perſon ſhould be deluded by the Devil by a falſe Revelation, for the ſpace of Twelve Years, and ſhould ſtill continue to be deluded?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> II. Since that this Perſon, by the means of this very Grace beſtow'd upon her, is come to receive <hi>Chriſt Jeſus</hi> accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to Truth, and to walk in him; how can this Revelation be from the Devil, which hath deſtroy'd in her the Devil's Work, and brought her to Chriſt?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> III. Since this Spirit, who reveals himſelf in her, calls himſelf the Spirit of Jeſus Chriſt, and witneſſes, that he who ſpeaks by her is the Lord <hi>Jehovah,</hi> the <hi>Tri-<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>n</hi> God, who Created Heaven and Earth, the God of <hi>Iſrael;</hi> how ſhould it be poſſible for <hi>Satan,</hi> ſo to diſguiſe himſelf in the form of an Angel of Light, as to give himſelf the Name of <hi>Jehovah,</hi> at which he cannot but tremble?</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="120" facs="tcp:38278:83" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <hi>Q.</hi> IV. Since that this Perſon has from her Childhood receiv'd ſome Revelations of di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſe great Myſteries, hidden in the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, which were not before known to us, and which by reaſon of their Profoundneſs, were not underſtood even by her ſelf, and which notwithſtanding do all ſhew ſo good<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly an Harmony: Likewiſe, ſince that ſhe knows not at all times how to write about ſuch Matters, but then only when ſhe is call'd by God, and hears his Voice: And ſince alſo that ſome Particulars have been foretold by her, which have really come to paſs accordingly: I deſire to be Anſwer'd, whether ſuch things as theſe can ever pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed from a ſtrong Imagination, or from a natural Subtilty of Spirit, of which yet there is nothing to be found in this dear Perſon, as all thoſe who knew her can te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtifie? And whether, though it may be without difficulty conſented to, that the Depths of Phanſie, of the Devil, and of his Deceivableneſs cannot, be all found out by us; it muſt <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> be alſo confeſs'd, that God will reveal theſe Depths and Heights of <hi>Satan,</hi> and of <hi>Reaſon,</hi> to his Children, by the Spirit, which he hath given them, which ſearcheth the Deep Things of God; to the end they may be able clearly to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern that which is the Fault of a ſtrong Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſion, from that which is the Effect of God's Spirit?</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="121" facs="tcp:38278:83"/>
               <head>XLII.</head>
               <p n="1">1. Before I conclude, I cannot forbear to inform you, my Dear Fathers and Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren in Chriſt, that ſuch abominable Lies and Slanders have been publiſh'd againſt Us, and Her, by the Father of Lies, and his Inſtruments, as we could never have be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liev'd it had been poſſible, if we had not been ſufficiently convinc'd of the Power of Darkneſs, which at this preſent rules in the World, in the midſt of thoſe who Name themſelves Chriſtians. We then call'd to Mind what the Lord had already, upon the 17th of <hi>June,</hi> foretold us; which was, that there ſhould ariſe great and abominable Miſtakes, the which ought not therefore to appear ſtrange to us, but rather to cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion us, that we may profit thereby, and be ſatisfy'd, that the Word and Teſtimony which have been given are True, in as much as they are ſo entirely accompliſh'd: Whereas if we had been of the World, we had been prais'd of it; and that every one might have ſpoken well of us, we needed to have done no more but to have expreſs'd our Doubt, whether theſe Revelations or Teſtimonies, were ſo Divine, as that we could be certain of their being ſo. This then is that Revelation, which the Lord gave for a Teſtimony to us.</p>
               <p>
                  <pb n="122" facs="tcp:38278:84"/>Peace be with you, my Elect: Again <hi>I</hi> ſpeak unto you, O ye that are Bleſſed, to the end I may quicken you, and that ye be not wearied in Patience and Stedfaſtneſs. Give ear now unto my kind Word, which in holy Love I communicate to you: Be ye elevated all ye Children of my Father, who loveth you, and become ſtrong in my Might, to the end ye may cleave ſtedfaſtly and immoveably to me, and depart not from me. For there will come abominable Lies, and groſs Miſtakes: Conſider it, for I have told it you, to the end ye may remain ſtedfaſt in my Truth, and well-grounded in the Faith, ſo as to depart neither to the Right Hand, nor to the Left. Let not a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny fear now overtake you, neither be at all diſquieted; for I the LORD, who am a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove the Heaven of all Heavens, am with you as a mighty Warriour, who go be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore you, and ſuffer you not to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy'd, if you truſt in Me, and remain with me. If ſo ye are faithful to Me, I am your ſtrong Defence, and your Caſtle: And who is he that ſhall ſurprize you, if ye are founded upon Me? As for the Evil-dealers that ſeek after you, they ſhall be broken in pieces, and ſhall fall heavily: But ye ſhall be made to rejoice in my great Help. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">
                  <pb n="123" facs="tcp:38278:84"/>2. Not long after this we were Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forted by the Lord, in like manner as one is comforted and elevated by one's Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther.</p>
               <p>Hear my Word, O <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and thou <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dah</hi> that art bleſſed of me, give good atten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion unto it: Lo, I come ſuddenly. Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtake not, move thou not thy foot, that thou mayeſt not fall: For mine Arm ſhall lead Thee, and unto thee ſhall my Truth be made manifeſt. At the Seventh Hour I will ſanctifie my Virgin, and will bring forth her Glory, which I give to her for a Refreſhment before the Riſing of the Sun. Be but of good Heart, my choſen Ones, without all manner of fear, for I have made a Covenant with you, that ye ſhall remain before Me: And now I Swear to you, yea, I JEHOVAH, the Lord of Hoſts, Swear to you, that for you I will ſet my Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs againſt all the High Things, which are lifted up againſt me, that am in you, and my Loving-kindneſs ſhall guide you, and my powerful Arm likewiſe ſhall be with you. This is the Covenant that I make with the Servants, and the Hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maids of <hi>Jacob.</hi> So verily as the Heaven is prepared by my Almighty Word, ſo keep I my Covenant with my Lambs, who ſhall leap after me upon Mount <hi>Gilead,</hi> and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Mount <hi>Sion</hi> my Fortreſs: Yea, I have
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:38278:85"/>
ſaid it: For I am the Lord, the LORD, who rule over the Cherubim and Seraphim, the God of <hi>Abraham,</hi> of <hi>Iſaac,</hi> and of <hi>Ja<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cob,</hi> who have bruiſed the Serpent's Head. Yea: <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Should we not then be Secure, and of a good Heart, ſince the Lord God of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> our Saviour thus Comforted us, and aſſur'd us of his Protection? It's no matter then how this appears in the ſight of the World, as if we were forſaken by him, and as if to us, who have plac'd our confidence in Him rather than in Man, all theſe ſweet and powerful Promiſes ſhould not have their Accompliſhment: We know notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, with the utmoſt and greateſt Certainty, that we ſhall not periſh, but ſhall Conquer, for that he hath loved us, <hi>Halle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lujah.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. Laſtly, upon the 30th of <hi>November,</hi> there came to us the following Word, in which the Lord explains to us what is the meaning of that paſſage, <hi>Mat.</hi> 24.23. <hi>Lo here is Chriſt, lo there is Chriſt:</hi> And he ſays, That the falſe Baſtard Spirit is already come into all States, and will yet come with more abominable Lying Wonders. The Warning is word for word this.</p>
               <p>I the Lord, LORD, Jeſus Chriſt, He that is True, do warn you, that you take
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:38278:85"/>
heed to your ſelves; for there are coming ſuch Falſe Chriſts, that are diſguiſed, and have ſuch an appearance of Godlineſs, as if it were poſſible the very Elect would be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived by them. For they have Tokens of Perfection, making to themſelves a Glory of true Humility; notwithſtanding which there is nothing in them, but Deceit and Abomination. As I live, I will deſtroy them, for they Propheſie by their own Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, with which the Starry Spirit is inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mixed, and bring forth many Wiſe Say<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, and ſay, I am he, I am he; believe me, for here is <hi>Immanuel;</hi> Chriſt is in me; he ſpeaks by me: But all this is meer de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit, they are Lies, and Fallen Spirits. Yet be not afraid, ye Lambs who hear my Voice; for ye ſhall be preſerved againſt the Hour of Temptation, for to Babes is the Myſtery diſcovered; and that which is Foo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh, and that which is Simple before the World, is that which I have prepared for my ſelf: And the Simple tread ſecurely, and that which is Nothing, I have choſen, and unto little Children is given the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly Wiſdom; to the end they may put to ſhame that which is lifted up in the Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Senſe; and that which is little, may put that which is exalted underneath it. Be not then afraid, ye Lambs, for unto you is given the true Wiſdom, to the end ye may
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:38278:86"/>
be certain, and able to diſcern; for ye have the pure Ointment, and the Spirit of Truth, whereby ye may know all the ſecret Plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſures, and become certain. Take heed, for the Falſe Spirit is now in all States, though not ſo powerfully, as he ſhall be.</p>
               <p>Judge now, my Fathers and Brethren beloved in Chriſt, a true Judgment in the Eyes of God: I earneſtly beſeech you, for the Univerſal Love of the Truth, and to the Publick Confeſſion of the Holy Won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders of God, to ſend me as ſoon as may be your Theological Anſwer. May the Lord JESUS, to whom this Matter appertains, be powerful with his Spirit in your Spirit: May he defend you with his Mighty Arm, againſt all the Gainſayers of his Holy Truth, and Crown you in the Day of the Reſurrection of the Righteous with Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting Glory. <hi>Amen.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>
                     <hi>I remain Your,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Moſt Obliged to Love and Prayer,</hi> J. W. P.</signed>
               </closer>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb n="127" facs="tcp:38278:86"/>
            <head>The Poſtſcript.</head>
            <p>IT having pleas'd our Good God and Saviour, by ſeveral Teſtimonies of the ſame kind, and Revelations given to Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons in many Places, and of all Sorts and Ranks, as Rich and Poor, Noble and <hi>Ple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beian,</hi> Learned and Unlearned, Men and Women, Young and Old, hidden from the World, but known to God; to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firm what he has Reveal'd by his Spirit in this Bleſſed Lady; I beſeech you Country<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and Brethren, from the Deep Centre of Love, to hearken to this one Sealing Teſtimony, which ſome few Years ſince, flow'd from the <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nity</hi> of the ſame Spirit to One in This Nation.</p>
            <p>I heard a Voice ſaying, Great ſilence in Heaven for half an Hour. Then there was a great Gathering together of many Saints and Angels before the Throne, and they ſeem'd in great Conſultation. And He that ſate on the Throne appear'd in great Glory, with a glorious Crown on his Head. Then I heard a Voice ſaying, Ariſe my Servant that art to go forth with the Ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>laſting
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:38278:87"/>
Goſpel; for I am coming forth with Ten Thouſands of my Saints to Judge the Earth. Pray and cry aloud, that Judgment may not break out in the Houſe of the Lord: Say, Spare thy Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, O Lord, and deliver thy Heritage; and let them not be conſumed with the Wicked. Mourn, O my People, betwixt the Porch and the Altar; ſo may ye pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent the Judgment that is coming forth. Behold I will put a Key into the Hand of my Servant, that is to go forth with the Everlaſting Goſpel; which will unlock the Heavens, and bring down a Bleſſing upon my People. Sing, O ye Heavens, and rejoice, O ye Saints, that live upon the Earth: For I will deliver you from the Adverſaries, by the mighty Hand of my Power. Faſt, and Pray, and your Cries ſhall be heard, and your Tears ſhall be ſhut up into my Bottle, for a Memorial before me: And ſuch as riſe up againſt you, ſhall fall before you.</p>
            <p>And I ſaw a Rainbow about the Throne, and the Voice ſaid, This ſhall be a Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant betwixt me and my People. Then I heard a great Voice, ſaying, I will come forth with Power, and will ſcatter ſuch as riſe up againſt the Everlaſting Goſpel. A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſe, ariſe my Servant, and put on my Strength, and come forth: For I am com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:38278:87"/>
to do great things upon the Earth. Howl ye Wicked, for I will pour out my Spirit on my Servants, and on my Hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maids; and they ſhall Propheſie, and their Propheſies ſhall come to paſs. Prepare your Hearts, O ye Saints, to meet your God, and I will fill your Hearts full of Joy and Rejoicing. For it is given to you to ſing the Song of Praiſes and Thanſgiv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings. Then ſhall the Daughters of <hi>Sion,</hi> be fill'd with Praiſes, and Songs of Deliver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance: For behold the King cometh with Triumph and Victory, and the Voice of the LORD ſhall be heard through the Earth. Then I beheld Four Cherubims clapping their Hands together, and cry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, Holy, Holy, Holy, Lord God of Sabbaoth: Heaven and Earth are full of thy Glory. Then I beheld a Glorious Throne in the midſt of Mount <hi>Sion,</hi> and Twenty Four Elders round about the Throne, and they threw down their Crowns, ſaying, <hi>Amen, Amen,</hi> ſo be it.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
